<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<sys-img:sdk-sys-img xmlns:sys-img="http://schemas.android.com/sdk/android/repo/sys-img2/03"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
	<!--Generated on 2023-02-09 17:20:35.214176 with ADRT.-->
	<license id="android-sdk-license" type="text">Terms and Conditions

This is the Android Software Development Kit License Agreement

1. Introduction

1.1 The Android Software Development Kit (referred to in the License Agreement as the &quot;SDK&quot; and specifically including the Android system files, packaged APIs, and Google APIs add-ons) is licensed to you subject to the terms of the License Agreement. The License Agreement forms a legally binding contract between you and Google in relation to your use of the SDK.

1.2 &quot;Android&quot; means the Android software stack for devices, as made available under the Android Open Source Project, which is located at the following URL: http://source.android.com/, as updated from time to time.

1.3 A &quot;compatible implementation&quot; means any Android device that (i) complies with the Android Compatibility Definition document, which can be found at the Android compatibility website (http://source.android.com/compatibility) and which may be updated from time to time; and (ii) successfully passes the Android Compatibility Test Suite (CTS).

1.4 &quot;Google&quot; means Google Inc., a Delaware corporation with principal place of business at 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, United States.


2. Accepting the License Agreement

2.1 In order to use the SDK, you must first agree to the License Agreement. You may not use the SDK if you do not accept the License Agreement.

2.2 By clicking to accept, you hereby agree to the terms of the License Agreement.

2.3 You may not use the SDK and may not accept the License Agreement if you are a person barred from receiving the SDK under the laws of the United States or other countries, including the country in which you are resident or from which you use the SDK.

2.4 If you are agreeing to be bound by the License Agreement on behalf of your employer or other entity, you represent and warrant that you have full legal authority to bind your employer or such entity to the License Agreement. If you do not have the requisite authority, you may not accept the License Agreement or use the SDK on behalf of your employer or other entity.


3. SDK License from Google

3.1 Subject to the terms of the License Agreement, Google grants you a limited, worldwide, royalty-free, non-assignable, non-exclusive, and non-sublicensable license to use the SDK solely to develop applications for compatible implementations of Android.

3.2 You may not use this SDK to develop applications for other platforms (including non-compatible implementations of Android) or to develop another SDK. You are of course free to develop applications for other platforms, including non-compatible implementations of Android, provided that this SDK is not used for that purpose.

3.3 You agree that Google or third parties own all legal right, title and interest in and to the SDK, including any Intellectual Property Rights that subsist in the SDK. &quot;Intellectual Property Rights&quot; means any and all rights under patent law, copyright law, trade secret law, trademark law, and any and all other proprietary rights. Google reserves all rights not expressly granted to you.

3.4 You may not use the SDK for any purpose not expressly permitted by the License Agreement.  Except to the extent required by applicable third party licenses, you may not copy (except for backup purposes), modify, adapt, redistribute, decompile, reverse engineer, disassemble, or create derivative works of the SDK or any part of the SDK.

3.5 Use, reproduction and distribution of components of the SDK licensed under an open source software license are governed solely by the terms of that open source software license and not the License Agreement.

3.6 You agree that the form and nature of the SDK that Google provides may change without prior notice to you and that future versions of the SDK may be incompatible with applications developed on previous versions of the SDK. You agree that Google may stop (permanently or temporarily) providing the SDK (or any features within the SDK) to you or to users generally at Google's sole discretion, without prior notice to you.

3.7 Nothing in the License Agreement gives you a right to use any of Google's trade names, trademarks, service marks, logos, domain names, or other distinctive brand features.

3.8 You agree that you will not remove, obscure, or alter any proprietary rights notices (including copyright and trademark notices) that may be affixed to or contained within the SDK.


4. Use of the SDK by You

4.1 Google agrees that it obtains no right, title or interest from you (or your licensors) under the License Agreement in or to any software applications that you develop using the SDK, including any intellectual property rights that subsist in those applications.

4.2 You agree to use the SDK and write applications only for purposes that are permitted by (a) the License Agreement and (b) any applicable law, regulation or generally accepted practices or guidelines in the relevant jurisdictions (including any laws regarding the export of data or software to and from the United States or other relevant countries).

4.3 You agree that if you use the SDK to develop applications for general public users, you will protect the privacy and legal rights of those users. If the users provide you with user names, passwords, or other login information or personal information, you must make the users aware that the information will be available to your application, and you must provide legally adequate privacy notice and protection for those users. If your application stores personal or sensitive information provided by users, it must do so securely. If the user provides your application with Google Account information, your application may only use that information to access the user's Google Account when, and for the limited purposes for which, the user has given you permission to do so.

4.4 You agree that you will not engage in any activity with the SDK, including the development or distribution of an application, that interferes with, disrupts, damages, or accesses in an unauthorized manner the servers, networks, or other properties or services of any third party including, but not limited to, Google or any mobile communications carrier.

4.5 You agree that you are solely responsible for (and that Google has no responsibility to you or to any third party for) any data, content, or resources that you create, transmit or display through Android and/or applications for Android, and for the consequences of your actions (including any loss or damage which Google may suffer) by doing so.

4.6 You agree that you are solely responsible for (and that Google has no responsibility to you or to any third party for) any breach of your obligations under the License Agreement, any applicable third party contract or Terms of Service, or any applicable law or regulation, and for the consequences (including any loss or damage which Google or any third party may suffer) of any such breach.

5. Your Developer Credentials

5.1 You agree that you are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of any developer credentials that may be issued to you by Google or which you may choose yourself and that you will be solely responsible for all applications that are developed under your developer credentials.

6. Privacy and Information

6.1 In order to continually innovate and improve the SDK, Google may collect certain usage statistics from the software including but not limited to a unique identifier, associated IP address, version number of the software, and information on which tools and/or services in the SDK are being used and how they are being used. Before any of this information is collected, the SDK will notify you and seek your consent. If you withhold consent, the information will not be collected.

6.2 The data collected is examined in the aggregate to improve the SDK and is maintained in accordance with Google's Privacy Policy.


7. Third Party Applications

7.1 If you use the SDK to run applications developed by a third party or that access data, content or resources provided by a third party, you agree that Google is not responsible for those applications, data, content, or resources. You understand that all data, content or resources which you may access through such third party applications are the sole responsibility of the person from which they originated and that Google is not liable for any loss or damage that you may experience as a result of the use or access of any of those third party applications, data, content, or resources.

7.2 You should be aware the data, content, and resources presented to you through such a third party application may be protected by intellectual property rights which are owned by the providers (or by other persons or companies on their behalf). You may not modify, rent, lease, loan, sell, distribute or create derivative works based on these data, content, or resources (either in whole or in part) unless you have been specifically given permission to do so by the relevant owners.

7.3 You acknowledge that your use of such third party applications, data, content, or resources may be subject to separate terms between you and the relevant third party. In that case, the License Agreement does not affect your legal relationship with these third parties.


8. Using Android APIs

8.1 Google Data APIs

8.1.1 If you use any API to retrieve data from Google, you acknowledge that the data may be protected by intellectual property rights which are owned by Google or those parties that provide the data (or by other persons or companies on their behalf). Your use of any such API may be subject to additional Terms of Service. You may not modify, rent, lease, loan, sell, distribute or create derivative works based on this data (either in whole or in part) unless allowed by the relevant Terms of Service.

8.1.2 If you use any API to retrieve a user's data from Google, you acknowledge and agree that you shall retrieve data only with the user's explicit consent and only when, and for the limited purposes for which, the user has given you permission to do so. If you use the Android Recognition Service API, documented at the following URL: https://developer.android.com/reference/android/speech/RecognitionService, as updated from time to time, you acknowledge that the use of the API is subject to the Data Processing Addendum for Products where Google is a Data Processor, which is located at the following URL: https://privacy.google.com/businesses/gdprprocessorterms/, as updated from time to time. By clicking to accept, you hereby agree to the terms of the Data Processing Addendum for Products where Google is a Data Processor.


9. Terminating the License Agreement

9.1 The License Agreement will continue to apply until terminated by either you or Google as set out below.

9.2 If you want to terminate the License Agreement, you may do so by ceasing your use of the SDK and any relevant developer credentials.

9.3 Google may at any time, terminate the License Agreement with you if:
(A) you have breached any provision of the License Agreement; or
(B) Google is required to do so by law; or
(C) the partner with whom Google offered certain parts of SDK (such as APIs) to you has terminated its relationship with Google or ceased to offer certain parts of the SDK to you; or
(D) Google decides to no longer provide the SDK or certain parts of the SDK to users in the country in which you are resident or from which you use the service, or the provision of the SDK or certain SDK services to you by Google is, in Google's sole discretion, no longer commercially viable.

9.4 When the License Agreement comes to an end, all of the legal rights, obligations and liabilities that you and Google have benefited from, been subject to (or which have accrued over time whilst the License Agreement has been in force) or which are expressed to continue indefinitely, shall be unaffected by this cessation, and the provisions of paragraph 14.7 shall continue to apply to such rights, obligations and liabilities indefinitely.


10. DISCLAIMER OF WARRANTIES

10.1 YOU EXPRESSLY UNDERSTAND AND AGREE THAT YOUR USE OF THE SDK IS AT YOUR SOLE RISK AND THAT THE SDK IS PROVIDED &quot;AS IS&quot; AND &quot;AS AVAILABLE&quot; WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND FROM GOOGLE.

10.2 YOUR USE OF THE SDK AND ANY MATERIAL DOWNLOADED OR OTHERWISE OBTAINED THROUGH THE USE OF THE SDK IS AT YOUR OWN DISCRETION AND RISK AND YOU ARE SOLELY RESPONSIBLE FOR ANY DAMAGE TO YOUR COMPUTER SYSTEM OR OTHER DEVICE OR LOSS OF DATA THAT RESULTS FROM SUCH USE.

10.3 GOOGLE FURTHER EXPRESSLY DISCLAIMS ALL WARRANTIES AND CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, WHETHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES AND CONDITIONS OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NON-INFRINGEMENT.


11. LIMITATION OF LIABILITY

11.1 YOU EXPRESSLY UNDERSTAND AND AGREE THAT GOOGLE, ITS SUBSIDIARIES AND AFFILIATES, AND ITS LICENSORS SHALL NOT BE LIABLE TO YOU UNDER ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, CONSEQUENTIAL OR EXEMPLARY DAMAGES THAT MAY BE INCURRED BY YOU, INCLUDING ANY LOSS OF DATA, WHETHER OR NOT GOOGLE OR ITS REPRESENTATIVES HAVE BEEN ADVISED OF OR SHOULD HAVE BEEN AWARE OF THE POSSIBILITY OF ANY SUCH LOSSES ARISING.


12. Indemnification

12.1 To the maximum extent permitted by law, you agree to defend, indemnify and hold harmless Google, its affiliates and their respective directors, officers, employees and agents from and against any and all claims, actions, suits or proceedings, as well as any and all losses, liabilities, damages, costs and expenses (including reasonable attorneys fees) arising out of or accruing from (a) your use of the SDK, (b) any application you develop on the SDK that infringes any copyright, trademark, trade secret, trade dress, patent or other intellectual property right of any person or defames any person or violates their rights of publicity or privacy, and (c) any non-compliance by you with the License Agreement.


13. Changes to the License Agreement

13.1 Google may make changes to the License Agreement as it distributes new versions of the SDK. When these changes are made, Google will make a new version of the License Agreement available on the website where the SDK is made available.


14. General Legal Terms

14.1 The License Agreement constitutes the whole legal agreement between you and Google and governs your use of the SDK (excluding any services which Google may provide to you under a separate written agreement), and completely replaces any prior agreements between you and Google in relation to the SDK.

14.2 You agree that if Google does not exercise or enforce any legal right or remedy which is contained in the License Agreement (or which Google has the benefit of under any applicable law), this will not be taken to be a formal waiver of Google's rights and that those rights or remedies will still be available to Google.

14.3 If any court of law, having the jurisdiction to decide on this matter, rules that any provision of the License Agreement is invalid, then that provision will be removed from the License Agreement without affecting the rest of the License Agreement. The remaining provisions of the License Agreement will continue to be valid and enforceable.

14.4 You acknowledge and agree that each member of the group of companies of which Google is the parent shall be third party beneficiaries to the License Agreement and that such other companies shall be entitled to directly enforce, and rely upon, any provision of the License Agreement that confers a benefit on (or rights in favor of) them. Other than this, no other person or company shall be third party beneficiaries to the License Agreement.

14.5 EXPORT RESTRICTIONS. THE SDK IS SUBJECT TO UNITED STATES EXPORT LAWS AND REGULATIONS. YOU MUST COMPLY WITH ALL DOMESTIC AND INTERNATIONAL EXPORT LAWS AND REGULATIONS THAT APPLY TO THE SDK. THESE LAWS INCLUDE RESTRICTIONS ON DESTINATIONS, END USERS AND END USE.

14.6 The rights granted in the License Agreement may not be assigned or transferred by either you or Google without the prior written approval of the other party. Neither you nor Google shall be permitted to delegate their responsibilities or obligations under the License Agreement without the prior written approval of the other party.

14.7 The License Agreement, and your relationship with Google under the License Agreement, shall be governed by the laws of the State of California without regard to its conflict of laws provisions. You and Google agree to submit to the exclusive jurisdiction of the courts located within the county of Santa Clara, California to resolve any legal matter arising from the License Agreement. Notwithstanding this, you agree that Google shall still be allowed to apply for injunctive remedies (or an equivalent type of urgent legal relief) in any jurisdiction.


January 16, 2019</license>
	<license id="android-sdk-preview-license" type="text">To get started with the Android SDK Preview, you must agree to the following terms and conditions.
As described below, please note that this is a preview version of the Android SDK, subject to change, that you use at your own risk.  The Android SDK Preview is not a stable release, and may contain errors and defects that can result in serious damage to your computer systems, devices and data.

This is the Android SDK Preview License Agreement (the &quot;License Agreement&quot;).

1. Introduction

1.1 The Android SDK Preview (referred to in the License Agreement as the “Preview” and specifically including the Android system files, packaged APIs, and Preview library files, if and when they are made available) is licensed to you subject to the terms of the License Agreement. The License Agreement forms a legally binding contract between you and Google in relation to your use of the Preview.

1.2 &quot;Android&quot; means the Android software stack for devices, as made available under the Android Open Source Project, which is located at the following URL: http://source.android.com/, as updated from time to time.

1.3 &quot;Google&quot; means Google Inc., a Delaware corporation with principal place of business at 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, United States.

2. Accepting the License Agreement

2.1 In order to use the Preview, you must first agree to the License Agreement. You may not use the Preview if you do not accept the License Agreement.

2.2 By clicking to accept and/or using the Preview, you hereby agree to the terms of the License Agreement.

2.3 You may not use the Preview and may not accept the License Agreement if you are a person barred from receiving the Preview under the laws of the United States or other countries including the country in which you are resident or from which you use the Preview.

2.4 If you will use the Preview internally within your company or organization you agree to be bound by the License Agreement on behalf of your employer or other entity, and you represent and warrant that you have full legal authority to bind your employer or such entity to the License Agreement. If you do not have the requisite authority, you may not accept the License Agreement or use the Preview on behalf of your employer or other entity.

3. Preview License from Google

3.1 Subject to the terms of the License Agreement, Google grants you a royalty-free, non-assignable, non-exclusive, non-sublicensable, limited, revocable license to use the Preview, personally or internally within your company or organization, solely to develop applications to run on the Android platform.

3.2 You agree that Google or third parties owns all legal right, title and interest in and to the Preview, including any Intellectual Property Rights that subsist in the Preview. &quot;Intellectual Property Rights&quot; means any and all rights under patent law, copyright law, trade secret law, trademark law, and any and all other proprietary rights. Google reserves all rights not expressly granted to you.

3.3 You may not use the Preview for any purpose not expressly permitted by the License Agreement. Except to the extent required by applicable third party licenses, you may not: (a) copy (except for backup purposes), modify, adapt, redistribute, decompile, reverse engineer, disassemble, or create derivative works of the Preview or any part of the Preview; or (b) load any part of the Preview onto a mobile handset or any other hardware device except a personal computer, combine any part of the Preview with other software, or distribute any software or device incorporating a part of the Preview.

3.4 You agree that you will not take any actions that may cause or result in the fragmentation of Android, including but not limited to distributing, participating in the creation of, or promoting in any way a software development kit derived from the Preview.

3.5 Use, reproduction and distribution of components of the Preview licensed under an open source software license are governed solely by the terms of that open source software license and not the License Agreement. You agree to remain a licensee in good standing in regard to such open source software licenses under all the rights granted and to refrain from any actions that may terminate, suspend, or breach such rights.

3.6 You agree that the form and nature of the Preview that Google provides may change without prior notice to you and that future versions of the Preview may be incompatible with applications developed on previous versions of the Preview. You agree that Google may stop (permanently or temporarily) providing the Preview (or any features within the Preview) to you or to users generally at Google's sole discretion, without prior notice to you.

3.7 Nothing in the License Agreement gives you a right to use any of Google's trade names, trademarks, service marks, logos, domain names, or other distinctive brand features.

3.8 You agree that you will not remove, obscure, or alter any proprietary rights notices (including copyright and trademark notices) that may be affixed to or contained within the Preview.

4. Use of the Preview by You

4.1 Google agrees that nothing in the License Agreement gives Google any right, title or interest from you (or your licensors) under the License Agreement in or to any software applications that you develop using the Preview, including any intellectual property rights that subsist in those applications.

4.2 You agree to use the Preview and write applications only for purposes that are permitted by (a) the License Agreement, and (b) any applicable law, regulation or generally accepted practices or guidelines in the relevant jurisdictions (including any laws regarding the export of data or software to and from the United States or other relevant countries).

4.3 You agree that if you use the Preview to develop applications, you will protect the privacy and legal rights of users. If users provide you with user names, passwords, or other login information or personal information, you must make the users aware that the information will be available to your application, and you must provide legally adequate privacy notice and protection for those users. If your application stores personal or sensitive information provided by users, it must do so securely. If users provide you with Google Account information, your application may only use that information to access the user's Google Account when, and for the limited purposes for which, each user has given you permission to do so.

4.4 You agree that you will not engage in any activity with the Preview, including the development or distribution of an application, that interferes with, disrupts, damages, or accesses in an unauthorized manner the servers, networks, or other properties or services of Google or any third party.

4.5 You agree that you are solely responsible for (and that Google has no responsibility to you or to any third party for) any data, content, or resources that you create, transmit or display through Android and/or applications for Android, and for the consequences of your actions (including any loss or damage which Google may suffer) by doing so.

4.6 You agree that you are solely responsible for (and that Google has no responsibility to you or to any third party for) any breach of your obligations under the License Agreement, any applicable third party contract or Terms of Service, or any applicable law or regulation, and for the consequences (including any loss or damage which Google or any third party may suffer) of any such breach.

4.7 The Preview is in development, and your testing and feedback are an important part of the development process. By using the Preview, you acknowledge that implementation of some features are still under development and that you should not rely on the Preview having the full functionality of a stable release. You agree not to publicly distribute or ship any application using this Preview as this Preview will no longer be supported after the official Android SDK is released.

5. Your Developer Credentials

5.1 You agree that you are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of any developer credentials that may be issued to you by Google or which you may choose yourself and that you will be solely responsible for all applications that are developed under your developer credentials.

6. Privacy and Information

6.1 In order to continually innovate and improve the Preview, Google may collect certain usage statistics from the software including but not limited to a unique identifier, associated IP address, version number of the software, and information on which tools and/or services in the Preview are being used and how they are being used. Before any of this information is collected, the Preview will notify you and seek your consent. If you withhold consent, the information will not be collected.

6.2 The data collected is examined in the aggregate to improve the Preview and is maintained in accordance with Google's Privacy Policy located at http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/.

7. Third Party Applications

7.1 If you use the Preview to run applications developed by a third party or that access data, content or resources provided by a third party, you agree that Google is not responsible for those applications, data, content, or resources. You understand that all data, content or resources which you may access through such third party applications are the sole responsibility of the person from which they originated and that Google is not liable for any loss or damage that you may experience as a result of the use or access of any of those third party applications, data, content, or resources.

7.2 You should be aware the data, content, and resources presented to you through such a third party application may be protected by intellectual property rights which are owned by the providers (or by other persons or companies on their behalf). You may not modify, rent, lease, loan, sell, distribute or create derivative works based on these data, content, or resources (either in whole or in part) unless you have been specifically given permission to do so by the relevant owners.

7.3 You acknowledge that your use of such third party applications, data, content, or resources may be subject to separate terms between you and the relevant third party.

8. Using Google APIs

8.1 Google APIs

8.1.1 If you use any API to retrieve data from Google, you acknowledge that the data may be protected by intellectual property rights which are owned by Google or those parties that provide the data (or by other persons or companies on their behalf). Your use of any such API may be subject to additional Terms of Service. You may not modify, rent, lease, loan, sell, distribute or create derivative works based on this data (either in whole or in part) unless allowed by the relevant Terms of Service.

8.1.2 If you use any API to retrieve a user's data from Google, you acknowledge and agree that you shall retrieve data only with the user's explicit consent and only when, and for the limited purposes for which, the user has given you permission to do so.

9. Terminating the License Agreement

9.1 the License Agreement will continue to apply until terminated by either you or Google as set out below.

9.2 If you want to terminate the License Agreement, you may do so by ceasing your use of the Preview and any relevant developer credentials.

9.3 Google may at any time, terminate the License Agreement, with or without cause, upon notice to you.

9.4 The License Agreement will automatically terminate without notice or other action upon the earlier of:
(A) when Google ceases to provide the Preview or certain parts of the Preview to users in the country in which you are resident or from which you use the service; and
(B) Google issues a final release version of the Android SDK.

9.5 When the License Agreement is terminated, the license granted to you in the License Agreement will terminate, you will immediately cease all use of the Preview, and the provisions of paragraphs 10, 11, 12 and 14 shall survive indefinitely.

10. DISCLAIMERS

10.1 YOU EXPRESSLY UNDERSTAND AND AGREE THAT YOUR USE OF THE PREVIEW IS AT YOUR SOLE RISK AND THAT THE PREVIEW IS PROVIDED &quot;AS IS&quot; AND &quot;AS AVAILABLE&quot; WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND FROM GOOGLE.

10.2 YOUR USE OF THE PREVIEW AND ANY MATERIAL DOWNLOADED OR OTHERWISE OBTAINED THROUGH THE USE OF THE PREVIEW IS AT YOUR OWN DISCRETION AND RISK AND YOU ARE SOLELY RESPONSIBLE FOR ANY DAMAGE TO YOUR COMPUTER SYSTEM OR OTHER DEVICE OR LOSS OF DATA THAT RESULTS FROM SUCH USE. WITHOUT LIMITING THE FOREGOING, YOU UNDERSTAND THAT THE PREVIEW IS NOT A STABLE RELEASE AND MAY CONTAIN ERRORS, DEFECTS AND SECURITY VULNERABILITIES THAT CAN RESULT IN SIGNIFICANT DAMAGE, INCLUDING THE COMPLETE, IRRECOVERABLE LOSS OF USE OF YOUR COMPUTER SYSTEM OR OTHER DEVICE.

10.3 GOOGLE FURTHER EXPRESSLY DISCLAIMS ALL WARRANTIES AND CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, WHETHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES AND CONDITIONS OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NON-INFRINGEMENT.

11. LIMITATION OF LIABILITY

11.1 YOU EXPRESSLY UNDERSTAND AND AGREE THAT GOOGLE, ITS SUBSIDIARIES AND AFFILIATES, AND ITS LICENSORS SHALL NOT BE LIABLE TO YOU UNDER ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, CONSEQUENTIAL OR EXEMPLARY DAMAGES THAT MAY BE INCURRED BY YOU, INCLUDING ANY LOSS OF DATA, WHETHER OR NOT GOOGLE OR ITS REPRESENTATIVES HAVE BEEN ADVISED OF OR SHOULD HAVE BEEN AWARE OF THE POSSIBILITY OF ANY SUCH LOSSES ARISING.

12. Indemnification

12.1 To the maximum extent permitted by law, you agree to defend, indemnify and hold harmless Google, its affiliates and their respective directors, officers, employees and agents from and against any and all claims, actions, suits or proceedings, as well as any and all losses, liabilities, damages, costs and expenses (including reasonable attorneys’ fees) arising out of or accruing from (a) your use of the Preview, (b) any application you develop on the Preview that infringes any Intellectual Property Rights of any person or defames any person or violates their rights of publicity or privacy, and (c) any non-compliance by you of the License Agreement.

13. Changes to the License Agreement

13.1 Google may make changes to the License Agreement as it distributes new versions of the Preview. When these changes are made, Google will make a new version of the License Agreement available on the website where the Preview is made available.

14. General Legal Terms

14.1 the License Agreement constitutes the whole legal agreement between you and Google and governs your use of the Preview (excluding any services which Google may provide to you under a separate written agreement), and completely replaces any prior agreements between you and Google in relation to the Preview.

14.2 You agree that if Google does not exercise or enforce any legal right or remedy which is contained in the License Agreement (or which Google has the benefit of under any applicable law), this will not be taken to be a formal waiver of Google's rights and that those rights or remedies will still be available to Google.

14.3 If any court of law, having the jurisdiction to decide on this matter, rules that any provision of the License Agreement is invalid, then that provision will be removed from the License Agreement without affecting the rest of the License Agreement. The remaining provisions of the License Agreement will continue to be valid and enforceable.

14.4 You acknowledge and agree that each member of the group of companies of which Google is the parent shall be third party beneficiaries to the License Agreement and that such other companies shall be entitled to directly enforce, and rely upon, any provision of the License Agreement that confers a benefit on (or rights in favor of) them. Other than this, no other person or company shall be third party beneficiaries to the License Agreement.

14.5 EXPORT RESTRICTIONS. THE PREVIEW IS SUBJECT TO UNITED STATES EXPORT LAWS AND REGULATIONS. YOU MUST COMPLY WITH ALL DOMESTIC AND INTERNATIONAL EXPORT LAWS AND REGULATIONS THAT APPLY TO THE PREVIEW. THESE LAWS INCLUDE RESTRICTIONS ON DESTINATIONS, END USERS AND END USE.

14.6 The License Agreement may not be assigned or transferred by you without the prior written approval of Google, and any attempted assignment without such approval will be void. You shall not delegate your responsibilities or obligations under the License Agreement without the prior written approval of Google.

14.7 The License Agreement, and your relationship with Google under the License Agreement, shall be governed by the laws of the State of California without regard to its conflict of laws provisions. You and Google agree to submit to the exclusive jurisdiction of the courts located within the county of Santa Clara, California to resolve any legal matter arising from the License Agreement. Notwithstanding this, you agree that Google shall still be allowed to apply for injunctive remedies (or an equivalent type of urgent legal relief) in any jurisdiction.

June 2014.</license>
	<license id="intel-android-sysimage-license" type="text">Intel Corporation Internal Evaluation License Agreement for x86 Android* System Images for Android Software Development Kit (SDK)
This Internal Evaluation License Agreement (this &quot;Agreement&quot;) is entered into by and between Intel and you (as an individual developer or a legal entity -- identified below as Recipient). Intel shall provide the Evaluation Software to Recipient as described in accordance with the Internal Evaluation License Terms and Conditions.

Definitions.
These terms shall have the following meanings:

&quot;Intel&quot; or &quot;INTEL&quot;
Intel Corporation
With an Address of:
2200 Mission College Blvd.
Santa Clara, CA 95052
Office of the General Counsel
Mail Stop: RNB-4-51
Attn: Software and Services Group Legal

&quot;Evaluation Software&quot;
The x86 Android* emulator system images for Android  Software Development Kit (SDK), as provided by Intel.

INTERNAL EVALUATION LICENSE TERMS AND CONDITIONS

1. DEFINITIONS.

1.1 Additional Defined Terms. &quot;Agreement&quot;, &quot;Evaluation Software&quot;,  &quot;Intel&quot;, &quot;Non-disclosure Agreement&quot;, &quot;Recipient&quot;, and &quot;Effective Date&quot; shall have the meanings ascribed to them on the signature page(s) of this Agreement.

1.2 Evaluation Materials means, collectively, the Evaluation Software (in source and/or object code form) and documentation (including, without limitation, any design documents, specifications and other related materials) related to the Evaluation Software.

1.3 &quot;Open Source Software&quot; means any software that requires as a condition of use, modification and/or distribution of such software that such software or other software incorporated into, derived from or distributed with such software (a) be disclosed or distributed in source code form; or (b) be licensed by the user to third parties for the purpose of making and/or distributing derivative works; or (c) be redistributable at no charge. Open Source Software includes, without limitation, software licensed or distributed under any of the following licenses or distribution models, or licenses or distribution models substantially similar to any of the following: (a) GNUs General Public License (GPL) or Lesser/Library GPL (LGPL), (b) the Artistic License (e.g., PERL), (c) the Mozilla Public License, (d) the Netscape Public License, (e) the Sun Community Source License (SCSL), (f) the Sun Industry Source License (SISL), (g) the Apache Software license and (h) the Common Public License (CPL).

1.4 &quot;Pre-Release Materials&quot; means &quot;alpha&quot; or &quot;beta&quot; designated pre-release features, which may not be fully functional, which Intel may substantially modify in producing any production version of the Evaluation Materials and/or is still under development by Intel and/or Intels suppliers.

2. PURPOSE. Intel desires to provide the Evaluation Materials to Recipient solely for Recipient's internal evaluation of the Evaluation Software and other Intel products, to evaluate the desirability of cooperating with Intel in developing products based on the Evaluation Software and/or to advise Intel as to possible modifications to the Evaluation Software. Recipient may not disclose, distribute or make commercial use of the Evaluation Materials or any modifications to the Evaluation Materials.
THE EVALUATION MATERIALS ARE PROVIDED FOR EVALUATION PURPOSES ONLY AND MAY NOT BE DISTRIBUTED BY RECIPIENT OR INCORPORATED INTO RECIPIENTS PRODUCTS OR SOFTWARE. PLEASE CONTACT AN INTEL SALES REPRESENTATIVE TO LEARN ABOUT THE AVAILABILITY AND COST OF A COMMERICAL VERSION OF THE EVALUATION SOFTWARE.

3. TITLE. Title to the Evaluation Materials remains with Intel or its suppliers. Recipient shall not mortgage, pledge or encumber the Evaluation Materials in any way. Recipient shall return all Evaluation Materials, keeping no copies, upon termination or expiration of this Agreement.

4. LICENSE. Intel grants Recipient a royalty-free, personal, nontransferable, nonexclusive license under its copyrights to use the Evaluation Software only for the purposes described in paragraph 2 above. Unless otherwise communicated in writing by Intel to Recipient, to the extent the Evaluation Software is provided in more than one delivery or release (each, a &quot;Release&quot;) the license grant in this Section 4 and the Evaluation Period shall apply to each Release. Recipient may not make modifications to the Evaluation Software. Recipient shall not disassemble, reverse-engineer, or decompile any software not provided to Recipient in source code form.
EXCEPT AS PROVIDED HEREIN, NO OTHER LICENSE, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, BY ESTOPPEL OR OTHERWISE, TO ANY OTHER INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY RIGHTS IS GRANTED TO THE RECIPIENT.

5. NO OBLIGATION. Recipient shall have no duty to purchase or license any product from Intel. Intel and its suppliers shall have no obligation to provide support for, or develop a non-evaluation version of, the Evaluation Software or to license any version of it.

6. MODIFICATIONS. This Agreement does NOT obligate Recipient to provide Intel with comments or suggestions regarding Evaluation Materials. However, should Recipient provide Intel with comments or suggestions for the modification, correction, improvement or enhancement of (a) the Evaluation Materials or (b) Intel products or processes which may embody the Evaluation Materials, Recipient grants to Intel a non-exclusive, irrevocable, worldwide, royalty-free license, with the right to sublicense Intels licensees and customers, under Recipient intellectual property rights, the rights to use and disclose such comments and suggestions in any manner Intel chooses and to display, perform, copy, make, have made, use, sell, offer to sell, import, and otherwise dispose of Intels and its sublicensees products embodying such comments and suggestions in any manner and via any media Intel chooses, without reference to the source.

7. WARRANTY DISCLAIMER. INTEL AND ITS SUPPLIERS MAKE NO WARRANTIES WITH RESPECT TO EVALUATION MATERIALS, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING ANY IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, OR ANY IMPLIED WARRANTY OF NONINFRINGEMENT. THE EVALUATION MATERIALS ARE PROVIDED AS IS, WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND.

8. LIMITATION OF LIABILITY. INTEL AND ITS SUPPLIERS SHALL NOT BE LIABLE FOR ANY PROPERTY DAMAGE, PERSONAL INJURY, LOSS OF PROFITS, INTERRUPTION OF BUSINESS OR ANY SPECIAL, CONSEQUENTIAL OR INCIDENTAL DAMAGES, HOWEVER CAUSED, WHETHER FOR BREACH OF WARRANTY, CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY OR OTHERWISE. INTEL AND ITS SUPPLIERS DISCLAIM ALL LIABILITY, INCLUDING LIABILITY FOR INFRINGEMENT OF ANY INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY RIGHTS RELATING TO THE EVALUATION MATERIALS.

9. EXPIRATION. Intel may terminate this Agreement immediately after a breach by Recipient.

10. GENERAL.

10.1 Controlling Law. Any claims arising under or relating to this Agreement shall be governed by the internal substantive laws of the State of Delaware or federal courts located in Delaware, without regard to principles of conflict of laws. Each party hereby agrees to jurisdiction and venue in the courts of the State of Delaware for all disputes and litigation arising under or relating to this Agreement. The parties agree that the United Nations Convention on Contracts for the International Sale of Goods is specifically excluded from application to this Agreement. The parties consent to the personal jurisdiction of the above courts.

10.2 Remedies. Recipient acknowledges that any disclosure, commercialization, or public use of the Evaluation Materials would cause irreparable injury to Intel and consents to the grant of an injunction by any court of competent jurisdiction in the event of a threatened breach.

10.3 Assignment. Recipient may not delegate, assign or transfer this Agreement, the license granted or any of Recipients rights or duties hereunder, expressly, by implication, by operation of law, by way of merger (regardless of whether Recipient is the surviving entity) or acquisition, or otherwise and any attempt to do so, without Intels express prior written consent, shall be null and void. Intel may assign this Agreement, and its rights and obligations hereunder, in its sole discretion.

10.4 Entire Agreement. This Agreement constitutes the entire agreement between Recipient and Intel and supersedes in their entirety any and all oral or written agreements previously existing between Recipient and Intel with respect to the subject matter hereof. This Agreement supersedes any and all &quot;click-to-accept&quot; or shrink-wrapped licenses, in hard-copy or electronic form, embedded in or included with the Evaluation Materials. This Agreement may only be amended or supplemented by a writing that refers explicitly to this Agreement and that is signed by duly authorized representatives of Recipient and Intel. Without limiting the foregoing, terms and conditions on any purchase orders or similar materials submitted by Recipient to Intel, and any terms contained in Intels standard acknowledgment form that are in conflict with these terms, shall be of no force or effect.

10.5 Severability. In the event that any provision of this Agreement shall be unenforceable or invalid under any applicable law or be so held by applicable court decision, such unenforceability or invalidity shall not render this Agreement unenforceable or invalid as a whole, and, in such event, such provision shall be changed and interpreted so as to best accomplish the objectives of such unenforceable or invalid provision within the limits of applicable law or applicable court decisions.

10.6 Export Regulations / Export Control. Recipient shall not export, either directly or indirectly, any product, service or technical data or system incorporating the Evaluation Materials without first obtaining any required license or other approval from the U.S. Department of Commerce or any other agency or department of the United States Government. In the event any product is exported from the United States or re-exported from a foreign destination by Recipient, Recipient shall ensure that the distribution and export/re-export or import of the product is in compliance with all laws, regulations, orders, or other restrictions of the U.S. Export Administration Regulations and the appropriate foreign government. Recipient agrees that neither it nor any of its subsidiaries will export/re-export any technical data, process, product, or service, directly or indirectly, to any country for which the United States government or any agency thereof or the foreign government from where it is shipping requires an export license, or other governmental approval, without first obtaining such license or approval. Recipient also agrees to implement measures to ensure that foreign national employees are authorized to receive any information controlled by U.S. export control laws. An export is &quot;deemed&quot; to take place when information is released to a foreign national wherever located.

10.7 Special Terms for Pre-Release Materials. If so indicated in the description of the Evaluation Software, the Evaluation Software may contain Pre-Release Materials. Recipient hereby understands, acknowledges and agrees that: (i) Pre-Release Materials may not be fully tested and may contain bugs or errors; (ii) Pre-Release materials are not suitable for commercial release in their current state; (iii) regulatory approvals for Pre-Release Materials (such as UL or FCC) have not been obtained, and Pre-Release Materials may therefore not be certified for use in certain countries or environments and (iv) Intel can provide no assurance that it will ever produce or make generally available a production version of the Pre-Release Materials . Intel is not under any obligation to develop and/or release or offer for sale or license a final product based upon the Pre-Release Materials and may unilaterally elect to abandon the Pre-Release Materials or any such development platform at any time and without any obligation or liability whatsoever to Recipient or any other person.

10.8 Open Source Software. In the event Open Source software is included with Evaluation Software, such Open Source software is licensed pursuant to the applicable Open Source software license agreement identified in the Open Source software comments in the applicable source code file(s) and/or file header provided with Evaluation Software. Additional detail may be provided (where applicable) in the accompanying on-line documentation. With respect to the Open Source software, nothing in this Agreement limits any rights under, or grants rights that supersede, the terms of any applicable Open Source software license agreement.
ANY PRE-RELEASE MATERIALS ARE NON-QUALIFIED AND, AS SUCH, ARE PROVIDED POSSIBLY WITH FAULTS</license>
	<license id="mips-android-sysimage-license" type="text">MIPS Technologies, Inc. (“MIPS”) Internal Evaluation License Agreement for MIPS Android™ System Images for Android Software Development Kit (SDK):
This Internal Evaluation License Agreement (this &quot;Agreement&quot;) is entered into by and between MIPS and you (as an individual developer or a legal entity -- identified below as “Recipient”). MIPS shall make the Evaluation Software available to Recipient as described in accordance with the terms and conditions set forth below.

By clicking on the “Accept” button, downloading, installing, or otherwise using the Evaluation Materials (defined below), you agree to be bound by the terms of this Agreement effective as of the date you click “Accept” (the “Effective Date”), and if doing so on behalf of an entity, you represent that you are authorized to bind the entity to the terms and conditions of this Agreement. If you do not agree to be bound by the terms and conditions of this Agreement, do not download, install, or use the Evaluation Materials.

1. DEFINITIONS. These terms shall have the following meanings:

1.1 “MIPS” shall mean MIPS Technologies, Inc., a Delaware corporation having a principal place of business at: 955 East Arques Ave., Sunnyvale, CA 94085

1.2 “Evaluation Software” shall mean MIPS Android™ emulator system images for Android Software Development Kit (SDK), as made available to Recipient.

1.3 “Evaluation Materials&quot; means, collectively, the Evaluation Software (in source and/or object code form) and documentation (including, without limitation, any design documents, specifications, reference manuals, and other related materials) related to the Evaluation Software as made available to Recipient.

1.4 “Open Source Software” means any software that requires (as a condition of use, modification and/or distribution of such software) that such software or other software incorporated into, derived from or distributed with such software (a) be disclosed or distributed in source code form; or (b) be licensed by the user to third parties for the purpose of making and/or distributing derivative works; or (c) be redistributable at no charge. Open Source Software includes, without limitation, software licensed or distributed under any of the following licenses or distribution models, or licenses or distribution models substantially similar to any of the following: (a) GNU’s General Public License (GPL) or Lesser/Library GPL (LGPL), (b) the Artistic License (e.g., PERL), (c) the Mozilla Public License, (d) the Netscape Public License, (e) the Sun Community Source License (SCSL), (f) the Sun Industry Source License (SISL), (g) the Apache Software license and (h) the Common Public License (CPL).

1.5 “Pre-Release Materials” means “alpha” or “beta” designated pre-release features, which may not be fully functional, which MIPS may substantially modify in producing any production version of the Evaluation Materials, and/or which is still under development by MIPS and/or MIPS’ suppliers.

2. PURPOSE. MIPS desires to make the Evaluation Materials available to Recipient solely for Recipient's internal evaluation of the Evaluation Software to evaluate the desirability of cooperating with MIPS in developing products that are compatible with the Evaluation Software and/or to advise MIPS as to possible modifications to the Evaluation Software. Recipient may not disclose, distribute, modify (except to facilitate the above-mentioned internal evaluation), or make commercial use of the Evaluation Materials or any modifications of the Evaluation Materials.

THE EVALUATION MATERIALS ARE PROVIDED FOR EVALUATION PURPOSES ONLY AND MAY NOT BE MODIFIED (EXCEPT TO FACILITATE THE INTERNAL EVALUATION) OR DISTRIBUTED BY RECIPIENT OR INCORPORATED INTO RECIPIENT’S PRODUCTS OR SOFTWARE. PLEASE CONTACT A MIPS SALES REPRESENTATIVE TO LEARN ABOUT THE AVAILABILITY AND COST OF A COMMERCIAL VERSION OF THE EVALUATION SOFTWARE.

3. TITLE. Title to the Evaluation Materials remains with MIPS or its suppliers. Recipient shall not mortgage, pledge or encumber the Evaluation Materials in any way. Recipient shall return all Evaluation Materials, keeping no copies, upon termination or expiration of this Agreement.

4. LICENSE. MIPS grants Recipient a royalty-free, personal, nontransferable, nonexclusive license under its copyrights to use the Evaluation Software only for the purposes described in paragraph 2 above and only for a period beginning on the Effective Date and extending to the first anniversary of the Effective Date (the “Evaluation Period”). Unless otherwise communicated in writing by MIPS to Recipient, to the extent the Evaluation Software is provided in more than one delivery or release (each, a “Release”) the license grant in this Section 4 and the Evaluation Period shall apply to each Release, in which case the Evaluation Period shall begin on the date that the Release is made generally available and continue to the first anniversary of such date. Recipient may not make modifications to the Evaluation Software. Recipient shall not disassemble, reverse-engineer, or decompile any software that is not provided to Recipient in source code form.


EXCEPT AS PROVIDED HEREIN, NO OTHER LICENSE, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, BY ESTOPPEL OR OTHERWISE, TO ANY OTHER MIPS INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY RIGHTS IS GRANTED TO THE RECIPIENT. OTHER THAN AS EXPLICITLY SET FORTH IN PARAGRAPH 2 ABOVE, NO RIGHT TO COPY, TO REPRODUCE, TO MODIFY, OR TO CREATE DERIVATIVE WORKS OF, THE EVALUATION MATERIALS IS GRANTED HEREIN.

5. NO OBLIGATION. Recipient shall have no duty to purchase or license any product from MIPS. MIPS and its suppliers shall have no obligation to provide support for, or develop a non-evaluation version of, the Evaluation Software or to license any version of it.

6. MODIFICATIONS. This Agreement does not obligate Recipient to provide MIPS with comments or suggestions regarding Evaluation Materials. However, should Recipient provide MIPS with comments or suggestions for the modification, correction, improvement or enhancement of (a) the Evaluation Materials or (b) MIPS products or processes which may embody the Evaluation Materials, then Recipient agrees to grant and hereby grants to MIPS a non-exclusive, irrevocable, worldwide, fully paid-up, royalty-free license, with the right to sublicense MIPS’ licensees and customers, under Recipient’s Intellectual property rights, to use and disclose such comments and suggestions in any manner MIPS chooses and to display, perform, copy, make, have made, use, sell, offer to sell, import, and otherwise dispose of MIPS’ and its sublicensee’s products embodying such comments and suggestions in any manner and via any media MIPS chooses, without reference to the source.

7. WARRANTY DISCLAIMER. MIPS AND ITS SUPPLIERS MAKE NO WARRANTIES WITH RESPECT TO EVALUATION MATERIALS, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING ANY IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, OR ANY IMPLIED WARRANTY OF NONINFRINGEMENT WITH RESPECT TO THIRD PARTY INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY. RECIPIENT ACKNOWLEDGES AND AGREES THAT THE EVALUATION MATERIALS ARE PROVIDED “AS IS,” WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND.

8. LIMITATION OF LIABILITY. MIPS AND ITS SUPPLIERS SHALL NOT BE LIABLE FOR ANY PROPERTY DAMAGE, PERSONAL INJURY, LOSS OF PROFITS, INTERRUPTION OF BUSINESS OR FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, SPECIAL, CONSEQUENTIAL OR INCIDENTAL DAMAGES, HOWEVER CAUSED OR ALLEGED, WHETHER FOR BREACH OF WARRANTY, CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY OR OTHERWISE, INCLUDING WITHOUT LIMITATION, UNDER TORT OR OTHER LEGAL THEORY. MIPS AND ITS SUPPLIERS DISCLAIM ANY AND ALL LIABILITY, INCLUDING LIABILITY FOR INFRINGEMENT OF ANY INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY RIGHTS OF ANY KIND RELATING TO THE EVALUATION MATERIALS.

9. EXPIRATION. MIPS may terminate this Agreement immediately after a breach by Recipient or otherwise at MIPS’ reasonable discretion and upon five (5) business days’ notice to Recipient.

10. GENERAL.

10.1 Controlling Law. This Agreement shall be governed by California law excluding its choice of law rules. With the exception of MIPS’ rights to enforce its intellectual property rights and any confidentiality obligations under this Agreement or any licenses distributed with the Evaluation Materials, all disputes and any claims arising under or relating to this Agreement shall be subject to the exclusive jurisdiction and venue of the state and federal courts located in Santa Clara County, California. Each party hereby agrees to jurisdiction and venue in the courts set forth in the preceding sentence. The parties agree that the United Nations Convention on Contracts for the International Sale of Goods is specifically excluded from application to this Agreement. The parties consent to the personal jurisdiction of the above courts.

10.2 Remedies. Recipient acknowledges and agrees that any breach of confidentiality obligations under this Agreement or any licenses distributed with the Evaluation Materials, as well as any disclosure, commercialization, or public use of the Evaluation Materials, would cause irreparable injury to MIPS, and therefore Recipient agrees to consent to, and hereby consents to, the grant of an injunction by any court of competent jurisdiction in the event of an actual or threatened breach.

10.3 Assignment. Recipient may not delegate, assign or transfer this Agreement, the license granted or any of Recipient’s rights, obligations, or duties hereunder, expressly, by implication, by operation of law, by way of merger (regardless of whether Recipient is the surviving entity) or acquisition, or otherwise and any attempt to do so, without MIPS’ express prior written consent, shall be ineffective, null and void. MIPS may freely assign this Agreement, and its rights and obligations hereunder, in its sole discretion.

10.4 Entire Agreement. This Agreement constitutes the entire agreement between Recipient and MIPS and supersedes in their entirety any and all oral or written agreements previously existing between Recipient and MIPS with respect to the subject matter hereof. This Agreement may only be amended or supplemented by a writing that refers explicitly to this Agreement and that is signed or otherwise accepted by duly authorized representatives of Recipient and MIPS.

10.5 Severability. In the event that any provision of this Agreement is finally adjudicated to be unenforceable or invalid under any applicable law, such unenforceability or invalidity shall not render this Agreement unenforceable or invalid as a whole, and, in such event, such unenforceable or invalid provision shall be interpreted so as to best accomplish the objectives of such provision within the limits of applicable law or applicable court decisions.

10.6 Export Regulations / Export Control. Recipient shall not export, either directly or indirectly, any product, service or technical data or system incorporating the Evaluation Materials without first obtaining any required license or other necessary approval from the U.S. Department of Commerce or any other governing agency or department of the United States Government. In the event any product is exported from the United States or re-exported from a foreign destination by Recipient, Recipient shall ensure that the distribution and export/re-export or import of the product is in compliance with all applicable laws, regulations, orders, or other restrictions of the U.S. Export Administration Regulations and the appropriate foreign government. Recipient agrees that neither it nor any of its subsidiaries will export/re-export any technical data, process, product, or service, directly or indirectly, to any country for which the United States government or any agency thereof or the foreign government from where it is shipping requires an export license, or other governmental approval, without first obtaining such license or approval. Recipient also agrees to implement measures to ensure that foreign national employees are authorized to receive any information controlled by U.S. export control laws. An export is &quot;deemed&quot; to take place when information is released to a foreign national wherever located.

10.7 Special Terms for Pre-Release Materials. If so indicated in the description of the Evaluation Software, the Evaluation Software may contain Pre-Release Materials. Recipient hereby understands, acknowledges and agrees that: (i) Pre-Release Materials may not be fully tested and may contain bugs or errors; (ii) Pre-Release materials are not suitable for commercial release in their current state; (iii) regulatory approvals for Pre-Release Materials (such as UL or FCC) have not been obtained, and Pre-Release Materials may therefore not be certified for use in certain countries or environments or may not be suitable for certain applications and (iv) MIPS can provide no assurance that it will ever produce or make generally available a production version of the Pre-Release Materials . MIPS is not under any obligation to develop and/or release or offer for sale or license a final product based upon the Pre-Release Materials and may unilaterally elect to abandon the Pre-Release Materials or any such development platform at any time and without any obligation or liability whatsoever to Recipient or any other person.

ANY PRE-RELEASE MATERIALS ARE NON-QUALIFIED AND, AS SUCH, ARE PROVIDED “AS IS” AND “AS AVAILABLE”, POSSIBLY WITH FAULTS, AND WITHOUT REPRESENTATION OR WARRANTY OF ANY KIND.

10.8 Open Source Software. In the event Open Source software is included with Evaluation Software, such Open Source software is licensed pursuant to the applicable Open Source software license agreement identified in the Open Source software comments in the applicable source code file(s) and/or file header as indicated in the Evaluation Software. Additional detail may be available (where applicable) in the accompanying on-line documentation. With respect to the Open Source software, nothing in this Agreement limits any rights under, or grants rights that supersede, the terms of any applicable Open Source software license agreement.
	</license>
	<license id="android-googletv-license" type="text">Terms and Conditions

This is the Google TV Add-on for the Android Software Development Kit License Agreement.

1. Introduction

1.1 The Google TV Add-on for the Android Software Development Kit (referred to in this License Agreement as the &quot;Google TV Add-on&quot; and specifically including the Android system files, packaged APIs, and Google APIs add-ons) is licensed to you subject to the terms of this License Agreement. This License Agreement forms a legally binding contract between you and Google in relation to your use of the Google TV Add-on.

1.2 &quot;Google&quot; means Google Inc., a Delaware corporation with principal place of business at 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, United States.

2. Accepting this License Agreement

2.1 In order to use the Google TV Add-on, you must first agree to this License Agreement. You may not use the Google TV Add-on if you do not accept this License Agreement.

2.2 You can accept this License Agreement by:

(A) clicking to accept or agree to this License Agreement, where this option is made available to you; or

(B) by actually using the Google TV Add-on.  In this case, you agree that use of the Google TV Add-on constitutes acceptance of the License Agreement from that point onwards.

2.3 You may not use the Google TV Add-on and may not accept the Licensing Agreement if you are a person barred from receiving the Google TV Add-on under the laws of the United States or other countries including the country in which you are resident or from which you use the Google TV Add-on.

2.4 If you are agreeing to be bound by this License Agreement on behalf of your employer or other entity, you represent and warrant that you have full legal authority to bind your employer or such entity to this License Agreement. If you do not have the requisite authority, you may not accept the Licensing Agreement or use the Google TV Add-on on behalf of your employer or other entity.

3. Google TV Add-on License from Google

3.1 Subject to the terms of this License Agreement, Google grants you a limited, worldwide, royalty-free, non- assignable and non-exclusive license to use the Google TV Add-on solely to develop applications to run on the Google TV platform.

3.2 You agree that Google or third parties own all legal right, title and interest in and to the Google TV Add-on, including any Intellectual Property Rights that subsist in the Google TV Add-on. &quot;Intellectual Property Rights&quot; means any and all rights under patent law, copyright law, trade secret law, trademark law, and any and all other proprietary rights. Google reserves all rights not expressly granted to you.

3.3 Except to the extent required by applicable third party licenses, you may not copy (except for backup purposes), modify, adapt, redistribute, decompile, reverse engineer, disassemble, or create derivative works of the Google TV Add-on or any part of the Google TV Add-on. Except to the extent required by applicable third party licenses, you may not load any part of the Google TV Add-on onto a mobile handset, television, or any other hardware device except a personal computer, combine any part of the Google TV Add-on with other software, or distribute any software or device incorporating a part of the Google TV Add-on.

3.4 Use, reproduction and distribution of components of the Google TV Add-on licensed under an open source software license are governed solely by the terms of that open source software license and not this License Agreement.

3.5 You agree that the form and nature of the Google TV Add-on that Google provides may change without prior notice to you and that future versions of the Google TV Add-on may be incompatible with applications developed on previous versions of the Google TV Add-on. You agree that Google may stop (permanently or temporarily) providing the Google TV Add-on (or any features within the Google TV Add-on) to you or to users generally at Google's sole discretion, without prior notice to you.

3.6 Nothing in this License Agreement gives you a right to use any of Google's or it’s licensors’ trade names, trademarks, service marks, logos, domain names, or other distinctive brand features.

3.7 You agree that you will not remove, obscure, or alter any proprietary rights notices (including copyright and trademark notices) that may be affixed to or contained within the Google TV Add-on.

4. Use of the Google TV Add-on by You

4.1 Google agrees that it obtains no right, title or interest from you (or your licensors) under this License Agreement in or to any software applications that you develop using the Google TV Add-on, including any intellectual property rights that subsist in those applications.

4.2 You agree to use the Google TV Add-on and write applications only for purposes that are permitted by (a) this License Agreement and (b) any applicable law, regulation or generally accepted practices or guidelines in the relevant jurisdictions (including any laws regarding the export of data or software to and from the United States or other relevant countries).

4.3 You agree that if you use the Google TV Add-on to develop applications for general public users, you will protect the privacy and legal rights of those users. If the users provide you with user names, passwords, or other login information or personal information, your must make the users aware that the information will be available to your application, and you must provide legally adequate privacy notice and protection for those users. If your application stores personal or sensitive information provided by users, it must do so securely. If the user provides your application with Google Account information, your application may only use that information to access the user's Google Account when, and for the limited purposes for which, the user has given you explicit permission to do so.

4.4 You agree that you will not engage in any activity with the Google TV Add-on, including the development or distribution of an application, that interferes with, disrupts, damages, or accesses in an unauthorized manner the servers, networks, or other properties or services of any third party including, but not limited to, Google, Multichannel Video Program Distributors or any mobile communications carrier.

4.5 You agree that you are solely responsible for (and that Google has no responsibility to you or to any third party for) any data, content, or resources that you create, transmit or display through the Google TV platform and/or applications for the Google TV platform, and for the consequences of your actions (including any loss or damage which Google may suffer) by doing so.

4.6 You agree that you are solely responsible for (and that Google has no responsibility to you or to any third party for) any breach of your obligations under this License Agreement, any applicable third party contract or Terms of Service, or any applicable law or regulation, and for the consequences (including any loss or damage which Google or any third party may suffer) of any such breach.

5. Your Developer Credentials

5.1 You agree that you are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of any developer credentials that may be issued to you by Google or which you may choose yourself and that you will be solely responsible for all applications that are developed under your developer credentials.

6. Privacy and Information

6.1 In order to continually innovate and improve the Google TV Add-on, Google may collect certain usage statistics from the software including but not limited to a unique identifier, associated IP address, version number of the software, and information on which tools and/or services in the Google TV Add-on are being used and how they are being used. Before any of this information is collected, the Google TV Add-on will notify you and seek your consent. If you withhold consent, the information will not be collected.

6.2 The data collected is examined in the aggregate to improve the Google TV Add-on and is maintained in accordance with Google's Privacy Policy.

7. Third Party Applications for the Google TV Platform

7.1 If you use the Google TV Add-on to run applications developed by a third party or that access data, content or resources provided by a third party, you agree that Google is not responsible for those applications, data, content, or resources. You understand that all data, content or resources which you may access through such third party applications are the sole responsibility of the person from which they originated and that Google is not liable for any loss or damage that you may experience as a result of the use or access of any of those third party applications, data, content, or resources.

7.2 You should be aware the data, content, and resources presented to you through such a third party application may be protected by intellectual property rights which are owned by the providers (or by other persons or companies on their behalf). You may not modify, rent, lease, loan, sell, distribute or create derivative works based on these data, content, or resources (either in whole or in part) unless you have been specifically given permission to do so by the relevant owners.

7.3 You acknowledge that your use of such third party applications, data, content, or resources may be subject to separate terms between you and the relevant third party. In that case, this License Agreement does not affect your legal relationship with these third parties.

8. Using Google TV APIs

8.1 If you use any Google TV API to retrieve data from Google, you acknowledge that the data (“Google TV API Content”) may be protected by intellectual property rights which are owned by Google or those parties that provide the data (or by other persons or companies on their behalf). Your use of any such API may be subject to additional Terms of Service. You may not modify, rent, lease, loan, sell, distribute or create derivative works based on this data (either in whole or in part) unless allowed by the relevant Terms of Service.  Some portions of the Google TV API Content are licensed to Google by third parties, including but not limited to Tribune Media Services

8.2 If you use any API to retrieve a user's data from Google, you acknowledge and agree that you shall retrieve data only with the user's explicit consent and only when, and for the limited purposes for which, the user has given you permission to do so.

8.3 Except as explicitly permitted in Section 3 (Google TV Add-on License from Google), you must:

(a) not modify nor format the Google TV API Content except to the extent reasonably and technically necessary to optimize the display such Google TV API Content in your application;

(b) not edit the Google TV API Content in a manner that renders the Google TV API Content inaccurate of alters its inherent meaning (provided that displaying excerpts will not violate the foregoing); or

(c)  not create any commercial audience measurement tool or service using the Google TV API Content

9. Terminating this License Agreement

9.1 This License Agreement will continue to apply until terminated by either you or Google as set out below.

9.2 If you want to terminate this License Agreement, you may do so by ceasing your use of the Google TV Add-on and any relevant developer credentials.

9.3 Google may at any time, terminate this License Agreement with you if:

(A) you have breached any provision of this License Agreement; or

(B) Google is required to do so by law; or

(C) the partner with whom Google offered certain parts of Google TV Add-on (such as APIs) to you has terminated its relationship with Google or ceased to offer certain parts of the Google TV Add-on to you; or

(D) Google decides to no longer providing the Google TV Add-on or certain parts of the Google TV Add-on to users in the country in which you are resident or from which you use the service, or the provision of the Google TV Add-on or certain Google TV Add-on services to you by Google is, in Google's sole discretion, no longer commercially viable.

9.4 When this License Agreement comes to an end, all of the legal rights, obligations and liabilities that you and Google have benefited from, been subject to (or which have accrued over time whilst this License Agreement has been in force) or which are expressed to continue indefinitely, shall be unaffected by this cessation, and the provisions of paragraph 14.7 shall continue to apply to such rights, obligations and liabilities indefinitely.

10. DISCLAIMER OF WARRANTIES

10.1 YOU EXPRESSLY UNDERSTAND AND AGREE THAT YOUR USE OF THE GOOGLE TV ADD-ON IS AT YOUR SOLE RISK AND THAT THE GOOGLE TV ADD-ON IS PROVIDED &quot;AS IS&quot; AND &quot;AS AVAILABLE&quot; WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND FROM GOOGLE.

10.2 YOUR USE OF THE GOOGLE TV ADD-ON AND ANY MATERIAL DOWNLOADED OR OTHERWISE OBTAINED THROUGH THE USE OF THE GOOGLE TV ADD-ON IS AT YOUR OWN DISCRETION AND RISK AND YOU ARE SOLELY RESPONSIBLE FOR ANY DAMAGE TO YOUR COMPUTER SYSTEM OR OTHER DEVICE OR LOSS OF DATA THAT RESULTS FROM SUCH USE.

10.3 GOOGLE FURTHER EXPRESSLY DISCLAIMS ALL WARRANTIES AND CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, WHETHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES AND CONDITIONS OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NON-INFRINGEMENT.

11. LIMITATION OF LIABILITY

11.1 YOU EXPRESSLY UNDERSTAND AND AGREE THAT GOOGLE, ITS SUBSIDIARIES AND AFFILIATES, AND ITS LICENSORS SHALL NOT BE LIABLE TO YOU UNDER ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL CONSEQUENTIAL OR EXEMPLARY DAMAGES THAT MAY BE INCURRED BY YOU, INCLUDING ANY LOSS OF DATA, WHETHER OR NOT GOOGLE OR ITS REPRESENTATIVES HAVE BEEN ADVISED OF OR SHOULD HAVE BEEN AWARE OF THE POSSIBILITY OF ANY SUCH LOSSES ARISING.

12. Indemnification

12.1 To the maximum extent permitted by law, you agree to defend, indemnify and hold harmless Google, its affiliates and their respective directors, officers, employees and agents from and against any and all claims, actions, suits or proceedings, as well as any and all losses, liabilities, damages, costs and expenses (including reasonable attorneys fees) arising out of or accruing from (a) your use of the Google TV Add-on, (b) any application you develop on the Google TV Add-on that infringes any copyright, trademark, trade secret, trade dress, patent or other intellectual property right of any person or defames any person or violates their rights of publicity or privacy, and (c) any non-compliance by you with this License Agreement.

13. Changes to the License Agreement

13.1 Google may make changes to the License Agreement as it distributes new versions of the Google TV Add-on.

14. General Legal Terms

14.1 This License Agreement constitute the whole legal agreement between you and Google and govern your use of the Google TV Add-on (excluding any services which Google may provide to you under a separate written agreement), and completely replace any prior agreements between you and Google in relation to the Google TV Add-on.

14.2 You agree that if Google does not exercise or enforce any legal right or remedy which is contained in this License Agreement (or which Google has the benefit of under any applicable law), this will not be taken to be a formal waiver of Google's rights and that those rights or remedies will still be available to Google.

14.3 If any court of law, having the jurisdiction to decide on this matter, rules that any provision of this License Agreement is invalid, then that provision will be removed from this License Agreement without affecting the rest of this License Agreement. The remaining provisions of this License Agreement will continue to be valid and enforceable.

14.4 You acknowledge and agree that Google’s API data licensors and each member of the group of companies of which Google is the parent shall be third party beneficiaries to this License Agreement and that such other companies shall be entitled to directly enforce, and rely upon, any provision of this License Agreement that confers a benefit on (or rights in favor of) them. Other than this, no other person or company shall be third party beneficiaries to this License Agreement.

14.5 EXPORT RESTRICTIONS. THE GOOGLE TV ADD-ON IS SUBJECT TO UNITED STATES EXPORT LAWS AND REGULATIONS. YOU MUST COMPLY WITH ALL DOMESTIC AND INTERNATIONAL EXPORT LAWS AND REGULATIONS THAT APPLY TO THE GOOGLE TV ADD-ON. THESE LAWS INCLUDE RESTRICTIONS ON DESTINATIONS, END USERS AND END USE.

14.6 The rights granted in this License Agreement may not be assigned or transferred by either you or Google without the prior written approval of the other party. Neither you nor Google shall be permitted to delegate their responsibilities or obligations under this License Agreement without the prior written approval of the other party.

14.7 This License Agreement, and your relationship with Google under this License Agreement, shall be governed by the laws of the State of California without regard to its conflict of laws provisions. You and Google agree to submit to the exclusive jurisdiction of the courts located within the county of Santa Clara, California to resolve any legal matter arising from this License Agreement. Notwithstanding this, you agree that Google shall still be allowed to apply for injunctive remedies (or an equivalent type of urgent legal relief) in any jurisdiction.


August 15, 2011</license>
	<license id="android-sdk-arm-dbt-license" type="text">Terms and Conditions

This is the Android Software Development Kit License Agreement

1. Introduction

1.1 The Android Software Development Kit (referred to in the License Agreement as the &quot;SDK&quot; and specifically including the Android system files, packaged APIs, and Google APIs add-ons) is licensed to you subject to the terms of the License Agreement. The License Agreement forms a legally binding contract between you and Google in relation to your use of the SDK.

1.2 &quot;Android&quot; means the Android software stack for devices, as made available under the Android Open Source Project, which is located at the following URL: http://source.android.com/, as updated from time to time.

1.3 A &quot;compatible implementation&quot; means any Android device that (i) complies with the Android Compatibility Definition document, which can be found at the Android compatibility website (http://source.android.com/compatibility) and which may be updated from time to time; and (ii) successfully passes the Android Compatibility Test Suite (CTS).

1.4 &quot;Google&quot; means Google Inc., a Delaware corporation with principal place of business at 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, United States.


2. Accepting the License Agreement

2.1 In order to use the SDK, you must first agree to the License Agreement. You may not use the SDK if you do not accept the License Agreement.

2.2 By clicking to accept, you hereby agree to the terms of the License Agreement.

2.3 You may not use the SDK and may not accept the License Agreement if you are a person barred from receiving the SDK under the laws of the United States or other countries, including the country in which you are resident or from which you use the SDK.

2.4 If you are agreeing to be bound by the License Agreement on behalf of your employer or other entity, you represent and warrant that you have full legal authority to bind your employer or such entity to the License Agreement. If you do not have the requisite authority, you may not accept the License Agreement or use the SDK on behalf of your employer or other entity.


3. SDK License from Google

3.1 Subject to the terms of the License Agreement, Google grants you a limited, worldwide, royalty-free, non-assignable, non-exclusive, and non-sublicensable license to use the SDK solely to develop applications for compatible implementations of Android.

3.2 You may not use this SDK to develop applications for other platforms (including non-compatible implementations of Android) or to develop another SDK. You are of course free to develop applications for other platforms, including non-compatible implementations of Android, provided that this SDK is not used for that purpose.

3.3 You agree that Google or third parties own all legal right, title and interest in and to the SDK, including any Intellectual Property Rights that subsist in the SDK. &quot;Intellectual Property Rights&quot; means any and all rights under patent law, copyright law, trade secret law, trademark law, and any and all other proprietary rights. Google reserves all rights not expressly granted to you.

3.4 You may not use the SDK for any purpose not expressly permitted by the License Agreement.  Except to the extent required by applicable third party licenses, you may not copy (except for backup purposes), modify, adapt, redistribute, decompile, reverse engineer, disassemble, or create derivative works of the SDK or any part of the SDK.

3.5 Use, reproduction and distribution of components of the SDK licensed under an open source software license are governed solely by the terms of that open source software license and not the License Agreement.

3.6 You agree that the form and nature of the SDK that Google provides may change without prior notice to you and that future versions of the SDK may be incompatible with applications developed on previous versions of the SDK. You agree that Google may stop (permanently or temporarily) providing the SDK (or any features within the SDK) to you or to users generally at Google's sole discretion, without prior notice to you.

3.7 Nothing in the License Agreement gives you a right to use any of Google's trade names, trademarks, service marks, logos, domain names, or other distinctive brand features.

3.8 You agree that you will not remove, obscure, or alter any proprietary rights notices (including copyright and trademark notices) that may be affixed to or contained within the SDK.


4. Use of the SDK by You

4.1 Google agrees that it obtains no right, title or interest from you (or your licensors) under the License Agreement in or to any software applications that you develop using the SDK, including any intellectual property rights that subsist in those applications.

4.2 You agree to use the SDK and write applications only for purposes that are permitted by (a) the License Agreement and (b) any applicable law, regulation or generally accepted practices or guidelines in the relevant jurisdictions (including any laws regarding the export of data or software to and from the United States or other relevant countries).

4.3 You agree that if you use the SDK to develop applications for general public users, you will protect the privacy and legal rights of those users. If the users provide you with user names, passwords, or other login information or personal information, you must make the users aware that the information will be available to your application, and you must provide legally adequate privacy notice and protection for those users. If your application stores personal or sensitive information provided by users, it must do so securely. If the user provides your application with Google Account information, your application may only use that information to access the user's Google Account when, and for the limited purposes for which, the user has given you permission to do so.

4.4 You agree that you will not engage in any activity with the SDK, including the development or distribution of an application, that interferes with, disrupts, damages, or accesses in an unauthorized manner the servers, networks, or other properties or services of any third party including, but not limited to, Google or any mobile communications carrier.

4.5 You agree that you are solely responsible for (and that Google has no responsibility to you or to any third party for) any data, content, or resources that you create, transmit or display through Android and/or applications for Android, and for the consequences of your actions (including any loss or damage which Google may suffer) by doing so.

4.6 You agree that you are solely responsible for (and that Google has no responsibility to you or to any third party for) any breach of your obligations under the License Agreement, any applicable third party contract or Terms of Service, or any applicable law or regulation, and for the consequences (including any loss or damage which Google or any third party may suffer) of any such breach.

4.7 This software enables the execution of intellectual property owned by Arm Limited. You agree that your use of the software, that allows execution of ARM Instruction Set Architecture (“ISA”) compliant executables for application development and debug only on x86 desktop, laptop, customer on-premise servers, and customer-procured cloud-based environments.

5. Your Developer Credentials

5.1 You agree that you are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of any developer credentials that may be issued to you by Google or which you may choose yourself and that you will be solely responsible for all applications that are developed under your developer credentials.

6. Privacy and Information

6.1 In order to continually innovate and improve the SDK, Google may collect certain usage statistics from the software including but not limited to a unique identifier, associated IP address, version number of the software, and information on which tools and/or services in the SDK are being used and how they are being used. Before any of this information is collected, the SDK will notify you and seek your consent. If you withhold consent, the information will not be collected.

6.2 The data collected is examined in the aggregate to improve the SDK and is maintained in accordance with Google's Privacy Policy.


7. Third Party Applications

7.1 If you use the SDK to run applications developed by a third party or that access data, content or resources provided by a third party, you agree that Google is not responsible for those applications, data, content, or resources. You understand that all data, content or resources which you may access through such third party applications are the sole responsibility of the person from which they originated and that Google is not liable for any loss or damage that you may experience as a result of the use or access of any of those third party applications, data, content, or resources.

7.2 You should be aware the data, content, and resources presented to you through such a third party application may be protected by intellectual property rights which are owned by the providers (or by other persons or companies on their behalf). You may not modify, rent, lease, loan, sell, distribute or create derivative works based on these data, content, or resources (either in whole or in part) unless you have been specifically given permission to do so by the relevant owners.

7.3 You acknowledge that your use of such third party applications, data, content, or resources may be subject to separate terms between you and the relevant third party. In that case, the License Agreement does not affect your legal relationship with these third parties.


8. Using Android APIs

8.1 Google Data APIs

8.1.1 If you use any API to retrieve data from Google, you acknowledge that the data may be protected by intellectual property rights which are owned by Google or those parties that provide the data (or by other persons or companies on their behalf). Your use of any such API may be subject to additional Terms of Service. You may not modify, rent, lease, loan, sell, distribute or create derivative works based on this data (either in whole or in part) unless allowed by the relevant Terms of Service.

8.1.2 If you use any API to retrieve a user's data from Google, you acknowledge and agree that you shall retrieve data only with the user's explicit consent and only when, and for the limited purposes for which, the user has given you permission to do so. If you use the Android Recognition Service API, documented at the following URL: https://developer.android.com/reference/android/speech/RecognitionService, as updated from time to time, you acknowledge that the use of the API is subject to the Data Processing Addendum for Products where Google is a Data Processor, which is located at the following URL: https://privacy.google.com/businesses/gdprprocessorterms/, as updated from time to time. By clicking to accept, you hereby agree to the terms of the Data Processing Addendum for Products where Google is a Data Processor.


9. Terminating the License Agreement

9.1 The License Agreement will continue to apply until terminated by either you or Google as set out below.

9.2 If you want to terminate the License Agreement, you may do so by ceasing your use of the SDK and any relevant developer credentials.

9.3 Google may at any time, terminate the License Agreement with you if:
(A) you have breached any provision of the License Agreement; or
(B) Google is required to do so by law; or
(C) the partner with whom Google offered certain parts of SDK (such as APIs) to you has terminated its relationship with Google or ceased to offer certain parts of the SDK to you; or
(D) Google decides to no longer provide the SDK or certain parts of the SDK to users in the country in which you are resident or from which you use the service, or the provision of the SDK or certain SDK services to you by Google is, in Google's sole discretion, no longer commercially viable.

9.4 When the License Agreement comes to an end, all of the legal rights, obligations and liabilities that you and Google have benefited from, been subject to (or which have accrued over time whilst the License Agreement has been in force) or which are expressed to continue indefinitely, shall be unaffected by this cessation, and the provisions of paragraph 14.7 shall continue to apply to such rights, obligations and liabilities indefinitely.


10. DISCLAIMER OF WARRANTIES

10.1 YOU EXPRESSLY UNDERSTAND AND AGREE THAT YOUR USE OF THE SDK IS AT YOUR SOLE RISK AND THAT THE SDK IS PROVIDED &quot;AS IS&quot; AND &quot;AS AVAILABLE&quot; WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND FROM GOOGLE.

10.2 YOUR USE OF THE SDK AND ANY MATERIAL DOWNLOADED OR OTHERWISE OBTAINED THROUGH THE USE OF THE SDK IS AT YOUR OWN DISCRETION AND RISK AND YOU ARE SOLELY RESPONSIBLE FOR ANY DAMAGE TO YOUR COMPUTER SYSTEM OR OTHER DEVICE OR LOSS OF DATA THAT RESULTS FROM SUCH USE.

10.3 GOOGLE FURTHER EXPRESSLY DISCLAIMS ALL WARRANTIES AND CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, WHETHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES AND CONDITIONS OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NON-INFRINGEMENT.


11. LIMITATION OF LIABILITY

11.1 YOU EXPRESSLY UNDERSTAND AND AGREE THAT GOOGLE, ITS SUBSIDIARIES AND AFFILIATES, AND ITS LICENSORS SHALL NOT BE LIABLE TO YOU UNDER ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, CONSEQUENTIAL OR EXEMPLARY DAMAGES THAT MAY BE INCURRED BY YOU, INCLUDING ANY LOSS OF DATA, WHETHER OR NOT GOOGLE OR ITS REPRESENTATIVES HAVE BEEN ADVISED OF OR SHOULD HAVE BEEN AWARE OF THE POSSIBILITY OF ANY SUCH LOSSES ARISING.


12. Indemnification

12.1 To the maximum extent permitted by law, you agree to defend, indemnify and hold harmless Google, its affiliates and their respective directors, officers, employees and agents from and against any and all claims, actions, suits or proceedings, as well as any and all losses, liabilities, damages, costs and expenses (including reasonable attorneys fees) arising out of or accruing from (a) your use of the SDK, (b) any application you develop on the SDK that infringes any copyright, trademark, trade secret, trade dress, patent or other intellectual property right of any person or defames any person or violates their rights of publicity or privacy, and (c) any non-compliance by you with the License Agreement.


13. Changes to the License Agreement

13.1 Google may make changes to the License Agreement as it distributes new versions of the SDK. When these changes are made, Google will make a new version of the License Agreement available on the website where the SDK is made available.


14. General Legal Terms

14.1 The License Agreement constitutes the whole legal agreement between you and Google and governs your use of the SDK (excluding any services which Google may provide to you under a separate written agreement), and completely replaces any prior agreements between you and Google in relation to the SDK.

14.2 You agree that if Google does not exercise or enforce any legal right or remedy which is contained in the License Agreement (or which Google has the benefit of under any applicable law), this will not be taken to be a formal waiver of Google's rights and that those rights or remedies will still be available to Google.

14.3 If any court of law, having the jurisdiction to decide on this matter, rules that any provision of the License Agreement is invalid, then that provision will be removed from the License Agreement without affecting the rest of the License Agreement. The remaining provisions of the License Agreement will continue to be valid and enforceable.

14.4 You acknowledge and agree that each member of the group of companies of which Google is the parent shall be third party beneficiaries to the License Agreement and that such other companies shall be entitled to directly enforce, and rely upon, any provision of the License Agreement that confers a benefit on (or rights in favor of) them. Other than this, no other person or company shall be third party beneficiaries to the License Agreement.

14.5 EXPORT RESTRICTIONS. THE SDK IS SUBJECT TO UNITED STATES EXPORT LAWS AND REGULATIONS. YOU MUST COMPLY WITH ALL DOMESTIC AND INTERNATIONAL EXPORT LAWS AND REGULATIONS THAT APPLY TO THE SDK. THESE LAWS INCLUDE RESTRICTIONS ON DESTINATIONS, END USERS AND END USE.

14.6 The rights granted in the License Agreement may not be assigned or transferred by either you or Google without the prior written approval of the other party. Neither you nor Google shall be permitted to delegate their responsibilities or obligations under the License Agreement without the prior written approval of the other party.

14.7 The License Agreement, and your relationship with Google under the License Agreement, shall be governed by the laws of the State of California without regard to its conflict of laws provisions. You and Google agree to submit to the exclusive jurisdiction of the courts located within the county of Santa Clara, California to resolve any legal matter arising from the License Agreement. Notwithstanding this, you agree that Google shall still be allowed to apply for injunctive remedies (or an equivalent type of urgent legal relief) in any jurisdiction.


January 16, 2019</license>

	<license id="polestar-sdk-license" type="text">Conditions This is the Polestar Emulator License Agreement (the “License Agreement”). 1. Introduction 1.1 The Polestar Emulator (referred to in the License Agreement as the “Emulator” and contains Polestar developed system files as well as Android system files, packaged APIs, and library files provided by Google) is licensed to you subject to the terms of the License Agreement. The License Agreement forms a legally binding contract between you and Polestar and Google in relation to your use of the Emulator. 1.2 "Android" means the Android software stack for devices, as made available under the Android Open Source Project, which is located at the following URL: http://source.android.com/, as updated from time to time. 1.3 “Android-compatible” means any Android implementation that (i) complies with the Android Compatibility Definition document, which can be found at the Android compatibility website (http://source.android.com/compatibility) and which may be updated from time to time; and (ii) successfully passes the Android Compatibility Test Suite (CTS). 1.4 "Google" means Google LLC, a Delaware corporation with principal place of business at 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, United States. 1.5 “Polestar” means Polestar Performance AB with its principal place of business at Assar Gabrielssons Väg 9, 41878 Göteborg, Sweden. 1.6. “Licensor” means Google and Polestar jointly as parties. 2. Accepting the License Agreement 2.1 In order to use the Emulator, you must first agree to the License Agreement. You may not use the Emulator if you do not accept the License Agreement. 2.2 By clicking to accept and/or using the Emulator, you hereby agree to the terms of the License Agreement. 2.3 You may not use the Emulator and may not accept the License Agreement if you are a person barred from receiving the Emulator under the laws of the United States or other countries including the country in which you are resident or from which you use the Emulator. 2.4 If you will use the Emulator internally within your company or organization you agree to be bound by the License Agreement on behalf of your employer or other entity, and you represent and warrant that you have full legal authority to bind your employer or such entity to the License Agreement. If you do not have the requisite authority, you may not accept the License Agreement or use the Emulator on behalf of your employer or other entity. 3. Emulator License 3.1 Subject to the terms of this License Agreement, Licensor grants you a limited, worldwide, royalty-free, non-assignable, non-exclusive, and non-sublicensable license to use the Emulator solely to develop applications for compatible implementations of Android. 3.2 You may not use this Emulator to develop applications for other platforms (including non-compatible implementations of Android) or to develop another SDK. You are of course free to develop applications for other platforms, including non-compatible implementations of Android, provided that this Emulator is not used for that purpose. 3.3 You agree that Licensor or third parties owns all legal right, title and interest in and to the Emulator, including any Intellectual Property Rights that subsist in the Emulator. "Intellectual Property Rights" means any and all rights under patent law, copyright law, trade secret law, trademark law, and any and all other proprietary rights. Licensor reserves all rights not expressly granted to you. 3.4 You may not use the Emulator for any purpose not expressly permitted by the License Agreement. Except to the extent required by applicable third party licenses, you may not: (a) copy (except for backup purposes), modify, adapt, redistribute, decompile, reverse engineer, disassemble, or create derivative works of the Emulator or any part of the Emulator; or (b) load any part of the Emulator onto a mobile handset or any other hardware device except a personal computer, combine any part of the Emulator with other software, or distribute any software or device incorporating a part of the Emulator. 3.5 Use, reproduction and distribution of components of the Emulator licensed under an open source software license are governed solely by the terms of that open source software license and not the License Agreement. You agree to remain a licensee in good standing in regard to such open source software licenses under all the rights granted and to refrain from any actions that may terminate, suspend, or breach such rights. 3.6 You agree that the form and nature of the Emulator that Licensor provides may change without prior notice to you and that future versions of the Emulator may be incompatible with applications developed on previous versions of the Emulator. You agree that Licensor may stop (permanently or temporarily) providing the Emulator (or any features within the Emulator) to you or to users generally at Licensor’s sole discretion, without prior notice to you. 3.7 Nothing in the License Agreement gives you a right to use any of Licensor’s trade names, trademarks, service marks, logos, domain names, or other distinctive brand features. 3.8 You agree that you will not remove, obscure, or alter any proprietary rights notices (including copyright and trademark notices) that may be affixed to or contained within the Emulator. 4. Use of the Emulator by You 4.1 Licensor agrees that nothing in the License Agreement gives Licensor any right, title or interest from you (or your licensors) under the License Agreement in or to any software applications that you develop using the Emulator, including any intellectual property rights that subsist in those applications. 4.2 You agree to use the Emulator and write applications only for purposes that are permitted by (a) the License Agreement, and (b) any applicable law, regulation or generally accepted practices or guidelines in the relevant jurisdictions (including any laws regarding the export of data or software to and from the United States or other relevant countries). 4.3 You agree that if you use the Emulator to develop applications, you will protect the privacy and legal rights of users. If users provide you with user names, passwords, or other login information or personal information, you must make the users aware that the information will be available to your application, and you must provide legally adequate privacy notice and protection for those users. If your application stores personal or sensitive information provided by users, it must do so securely. If users provide you with Google Account information, your application may only use that information to access the user's Google Account when, and for the limited purposes for which, each user has given you permission to do so. 4.4 You agree that you will not engage in any activity with the Emulator, including the development or distribution of an application, that interferes with, disrupts, damages, or accesses in an unauthorized manner the servers, networks, or other properties or services of Google, Polestar, or any third party. 4.5 You agree that you are solely responsible for (and that Google and Polestar, independently or collectively, have no responsibility to you or to any third party for) any data, content, or resources that you create, transmit or display through Android and/or applications for Android, and for the consequences of your actions (including any loss or damage which Licensor may suffer) by doing so. 4.6 You agree that you are solely responsible for (and that Licensor has no responsibility to you or to any third party for) any breach of your obligations under the License Agreement, any applicable third party contract or Terms of Service, or any applicable law or regulation, and for the consequences (including any loss or damage which Google or any third party may suffer) of any such breach. 4.7 The Emulator is in development, and your testing and feedback are an important part of the development process. By using the Emulator, you acknowledge that implementation of some features are still under development and that you should not rely on the Emulator having the full functionality of a stable release. 5. Your Developer Credentials 5.1 You agree that you are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of any developer credentials that may be issued to you by Google or Polestar or which you may choose yourself and that you will be solely responsible for all applications that are developed under your developer credentials. 6. Privacy and Information 6.1 In order to continually innovate and improve the Emulator, Google and/or Polestar may collect certain usage statistics from the software including but not limited to a unique identifier, associated IP address, version number of the software, and information on which tools and/or services in the Emulator are being used and how they are being used. Before any of this information is collected, the Emulator will notify you and seek your consent. If you withhold consent, the information will not be collected. 6.2 The data collected is examined in the aggregate to improve the Emulator and is maintained in accordance with Google's Privacy Policy located at http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/. 7. Third Party Applications 7.1 If you use the Emulator to run applications developed by a third party or that access data, content or resources provided by a third party, you agree that neither Google nor Polestar is not responsible for those applications, data, content, or resources. You understand that all data, content or resources which you may access through such third party applications are the sole responsibility of the person from which they originated and that neither Google nor Polestar is liable for any loss or damage that you may experience as a result of the use or access of any of those third party applications, data, content, or resources. 7.2 You should be aware the data, content, and resources presented to you through such a third party application may be protected by intellectual property rights which are owned by the providers (or by other persons or companies on their behalf). You may not modify, rent, lease, loan, sell, distribute or create derivative works based on these data, content, or resources (either in whole or in part) unless you have been specifically given permission to do so by the relevant owners. 7.3 You acknowledge that your use of such third party applications, data, content, or resources may be subject to separate terms between you and the relevant third party. 8. Using Google APIs 8.1 Google APIs 8.1.1 If you use any API to retrieve data from Google, you acknowledge that the data may be protected by intellectual property rights which are owned by Google or those parties that provide the data (or by other persons or companies on their behalf). Your use of any such API may be subject to additional Terms of Service. You may not modify, rent, lease, loan, sell, distribute or create derivative works based on this data (either in whole or in part) unless allowed by the relevant Terms of Service. 8.1.2 If you use any API to retrieve a user's data from Google, you acknowledge and agree that you shall retrieve data only with the user's explicit consent and only when, and for the limited purposes for which, the user has given you permission to do so. 9. Terminating the License Agreement 9.1 The License Agreement will continue to apply until terminated by either you or Licensor as set out below. 9.2 If you want to terminate the License Agreement, you may do so by ceasing your use of the Emulator and any relevant developer credentials. 9.3 Google and/or Polestar may at any time, terminate the License Agreement, with or without cause, upon notice to you. 9.4 The License Agreement will automatically terminate without notice or other action when Licensor ceases to provide the Emulator or certain parts of the Emulator to users in the country in which you are resident or from which you use the service. 9.5 When the License Agreement is terminated, the license granted to you in the License Agreement will terminate, you will immediately cease all use of the Emulator, and the provisions of paragraphs 10, 11, 12 and 14 shall survive indefinitely. 10. DISCLAIMERS 10.1 YOU EXPRESSLY UNDERSTAND AND AGREE THAT YOUR USE OF THE EMULATOR IS AT YOUR SOLE RISK AND THAT THE EMULATOR IS PROVIDED "AS IS" AND "AS AVAILABLE" WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND FROM GOOGLE. 10.2 YOUR USE OF THE EMULATOR AND ANY MATERIAL DOWNLOADED OR OTHERWISE OBTAINED THROUGH THE USE OF THE EMULATOR IS AT YOUR OWN DISCRETION AND RISK AND YOU ARE SOLELY RESPONSIBLE FOR ANY DAMAGE TO YOUR COMPUTER SYSTEM OR OTHER DEVICE OR LOSS OF DATA THAT RESULTS FROM SUCH USE. WITHOUT LIMITING THE FOREGOING, YOU UNDERSTAND THAT THE EMULATOR IS NOT A STABLE RELEASE AND MAY CONTAIN ERRORS, DEFECTS AND SECURITY VULNERABILITIES THAT CAN RESULT IN SIGNIFICANT DAMAGE, INCLUDING THE COMPLETE, IRRECOVERABLE LOSS OF USE OF YOUR COMPUTER SYSTEM OR OTHER DEVICE. 10.3 GOOGLE FURTHER EXPRESSLY DISCLAIMS ALL WARRANTIES AND CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, WHETHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES AND CONDITIONS OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NON-INFRINGEMENT. 11. LIMITATION OF LIABILITY 11.1 YOU EXPRESSLY UNDERSTAND AND AGREE THAT GOOGLE AND/OR POLESTAR, NOT EITHER OF GOOGLE OR POLESTAR’S SUBSIDIARIES AND AFFILIATES, AND ITS LICENSORS SHALL BE LIABLE TO YOU UNDER ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, CONSEQUENTIAL OR EXEMPLARY DAMAGES THAT MAY BE INCURRED BY YOU, INCLUDING ANY LOSS OF DATA, WHETHER OR NOT GOOGLE AND/OR POLESTAR OR EITHER OF GOOGLE OR POLESTAR’S REPRESENTATIVES HAVE BEEN ADVISED OF OR SHOULD HAVE BEEN AWARE OF THE POSSIBILITY OF ANY SUCH LOSSES ARISING. 12. Indemnification 12.1 To the maximum extent permitted by law, you agree to defend, indemnify and hold harmless Google, its affiliates and their respective directors, officers, employees and agents and Polestar, its affiliates and their respective directors, officers, employees and agents from and against any and all claims, actions, suits or proceedings, as well as any and all losses, liabilities, damages, costs and expenses (including reasonable attorneys’ fees) arising out of or accruing from (a) your use of the Emulator, (b) any application you develop on the Emulator that infringes any Intellectual Property Rights of any person or defames any person or violates their rights of publicity or privacy, and (c) any non-compliance by you of the License Agreement. 13. Changes to the License Agreement 13.1 Licensor may make changes to the License Agreement as it distributes new versions of the Emulator. When these changes are made, Licensor will make a new version of the License Agreement available on the website where the Emulator is made available. 14. General Legal Terms 14.1 The License Agreement constitutes the whole legal agreement between you and Licensor and governs your use of the Emulator (excluding any services which Google and/or Polestar may provide to you under a separate written agreement), and completely replaces any prior agreements between you and Licensor in relation to the Emulator. 14.2 You agree that if Licensor does not exercise or enforce any legal right or remedy which is contained in the License Agreement (or which Licensor has the benefit of under any applicable law), this will not be taken to be a formal waiver of Licensor's rights and that those rights or remedies will still be available to Licensor. 14.3 If any court of law, having the jurisdiction to decide on this matter, rules that any provision of the License Agreement is invalid, then that provision will be removed from the License Agreement without affecting the rest of the License Agreement. The remaining provisions of the License Agreement will continue to be valid and enforceable. 14.4 You acknowledge and agree that each member of the group of companies of which Polestar and Google is each the parent shall be third party beneficiaries to the License Agreement and that such other companies shall be entitled to directly enforce, and rely upon, any provision of the License Agreement that confers a benefit on (or rights in favor of) them. Other than this, no other person or company shall be third party beneficiaries to the License Agreement. 14.5 EXPORT RESTRICTIONS. THE EMULATOR IS SUBJECT TO UNITED STATES EXPORT LAWS AND REGULATIONS. YOU MUST COMPLY WITH ALL DOMESTIC AND INTERNATIONAL EXPORT LAWS AND REGULATIONS THAT APPLY TO THE EMULATOR. THESE LAWS INCLUDE RESTRICTIONS ON DESTINATIONS, END USERS AND END USE. 14.6 The License Agreement may not be assigned or transferred by you without the prior written approval of Licensor, and any attempted assignment without such approval will be void. You shall not delegate your responsibilities or obligations under the License Agreement without the prior written approval of Licensor. 14.7 The License Agreement, and your relationship with Licensor under the License Agreement, shall be governed by the laws of the State of California without regard to its conflict of laws provisions. You and Licensor agree to submit to the exclusive jurisdiction of the courts located within the county of Santa Clara, California to resolve any legal matter arising from the License Agreement. Notwithstanding this, you agree that Licensor shall still be allowed to apply for injunctive remedies (or an equivalent type of urgent legal relief) in any jurisdiction.</license>
	<license id="volvo-sdk-license" type="text">Conditions This is the Volvo Cars Emulator License Agreement (the “License Agreement”). 1. Introduction 1.1 The Volvo Cars Emulator (referred to in the License Agreement as the “Emulator” and contains Volvo Cars developed system files as well as Android system files, packaged APIs, and library files provided by Google) is licensed to you subject to the terms of the License Agreement. The License Agreement forms a legally binding contract between you and Volvo Cars and Google in relation to your use of the Emulator. 1.2 "Android" means the Android software stack for devices, as made available under the Android Open Source Project, which is located at the following URL: http://source.android.com/, as updated from time to time. 1.3 “Android-compatible” means any Android implementation that (i) complies with the Android Compatibility Definition document, which can be found at the Android compatibility website (http://source.android.com/compatibility) and which may be updated from time to time; and (ii) successfully passes the Android Compatibility Test Suite (CTS). 1.4 "Google" means Google LLC, a Delaware corporation with principal place of business at 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, United States. 1.5. “Licensor” means Google and Volvo Cars jointly as parties. 1.6 “Volvo Cars” means Volvo Car Corporation with its principal place of business at 405 31 Göteborg, Sweden. 2. Accepting the License Agreement 2.1 In order to use the Emulator, you must first agree to the License Agreement. You may not use the Emulator if you do not accept the License Agreement. 2.2 By clicking to accept and/or using the Emulator, you hereby agree to the terms of the License Agreement. 2.3 You may not use the Emulator and may not accept the License Agreement if you are a person barred from receiving the Emulator under the laws of the United States or other countries including the country in which you are resident or from which you use the Emulator. 2.4 If you will use the Emulator internally within your company or organization you agree to be bound by the License Agreement on behalf of your employer or other entity, and you represent and warrant that you have full legal authority to bind your employer or such entity to the License Agreement. If you do not have the requisite authority, you may not accept the License Agreement or use the Emulator on behalf of your employer or other entity. 3. Emulator License 3.1 Subject to the terms of this License Agreement, Licensor grants you a limited, worldwide, royalty-free, non-assignable, non-exclusive, and non-sublicensable license to use the Emulator solely to develop applications for compatible implementations of Android. 3.2 You may not use this Emulator to develop applications for other platforms (including non-compatible implementations of Android) or to develop another SDK. You are of course free to develop applications for other platforms, including non-compatible implementations of Android, provided that this Emulator is not used for that purpose. 3.3 You agree that Licensor or third parties owns all legal right, title and interest in and to the Emulator, including any Intellectual Property Rights that subsist in the Emulator. "Intellectual Property Rights" means any and all rights under patent law, copyright law, trade secret law, trademark law, and any and all other proprietary rights. Licensor reserves all rights not expressly granted to you. 3.4 You may not use the Emulator for any purpose not expressly permitted by the License Agreement. Except to the extent required by applicable third party licenses, you may not: (a) copy (except for backup purposes), modify, adapt, redistribute, decompile, reverse engineer, disassemble, or create derivative works of the Emulator or any part of the Emulator; or (b) load any part of the Emulator onto a mobile handset or any other hardware device except a personal computer, combine any part of the Emulator with other software, or distribute any software or device incorporating a part of the Emulator. 3.5 Use, reproduction and distribution of components of the Emulator licensed under an open source software license are governed solely by the terms of that open source software license and not the License Agreement. You agree to remain a licensee in good standing in regard to such open source software licenses under all the rights granted and to refrain from any actions that may terminate, suspend, or breach such rights. 3.6 You agree that the form and nature of the Emulator that Licensor provides may change without prior notice to you and that future versions of the Emulator may be incompatible with applications developed on previous versions of the Emulator. You agree that Licensor may stop (permanently or temporarily) providing the Emulator (or any features within the Emulator) to you or to users generally at Licensor’s sole discretion, without prior notice to you. 3.7 Nothing in the License Agreement gives you a right to use any of Licensor’s trade names, trademarks, service marks, logos, domain names, or other distinctive brand features. 3.8 You agree that you will not remove, obscure, or alter any proprietary rights notices (including copyright and trademark notices) that may be affixed to or contained within the Emulator. 4. Use of the Emulator by You 4.1 Licensor agrees that nothing in the License Agreement gives Licensor any right, title or interest from you (or your licensors) under the License Agreement in or to any software applications that you develop using the Emulator, including any intellectual property rights that subsist in those applications. 4.2 You agree to use the Emulator and write applications only for purposes that are permitted by (a) the License Agreement, and (b) any applicable law, regulation or generally accepted practices or guidelines in the relevant jurisdictions (including any laws regarding the export of data or software to and from the United States or other relevant countries). 4.3 You agree that if you use the Emulator to develop applications, you will protect the privacy and legal rights of users. If users provide you with user names, passwords, or other login information or personal information, you must make the users aware that the information will be available to your application, and you must provide legally adequate privacy notice and protection for those users. If your application stores personal or sensitive information provided by users, it must do so securely. If users provide you with Google Account information, your application may only use that information to access the user’s Google Account when, and for the limited purposes for which, each user has given you permission to do so. 4.4 You agree that you will not engage in any activity with the Emulator, including the development or distribution of an application, that interferes with, disrupts, damages, or accesses in an unauthorized manner the servers, networks, or other properties or services of Google, Volvo Cars, or any third party. 4.5 You agree that you are solely responsible for (and that Google and Volvo Cars, independently or collectively, have no responsibility to you or to any third party for) any data, content, or resources that you create, transmit or display through Android and/or applications for Android, and for the consequences of your actions (including any loss or damage which Licensor may suffer) by doing so. 4.6 You agree that you are solely responsible for (and that Licensor has no responsibility to you or to any third party for) any breach of your obligations under the License Agreement, any applicable third party contract or Terms of Service, or any applicable law or regulation, and for the consequences (including any loss or damage which Google or any third party may suffer) of any such breach. 4.7 The Emulator is in development, and your testing and feedback are an important part of the development process. By using the Emulator, you acknowledge that implementation of some features are still under development and that you should not rely on the Emulator having the full functionality of a stable release. 5. Your Developer Credentials 5.1 You agree that you are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of any developer credentials that may be issued to you by Google or Volvo Cars or which you may choose yourself and that you will be solely responsible for all applications that are developed under your developer credentials. 6. Privacy and Information 6.1 In order to continually innovate and improve the Emulator, Google and/or Volvo Cars may collect certain usage statistics from the software including but not limited to a unique identifier, associated IP address, version number of the software, and information on which tools and/or services in the Emulator are being used and how they are being used. Before any of this information is collected, the Emulator will notify you and seek your consent. If you withhold consent, the information will not be collected. 6.2 The data collected is examined in the aggregate to improve the Emulator and is maintained in accordance with Google’s Privacy Policy located at http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/. 7. Third Party Applications 7.1 If you use the Emulator to run applications developed by a third party or that access data, content or resources provided by a third party, you agree that neither Google nor Volvo Cars is not responsible for those applications, data, content, or resources. You understand that all data, content or resources which you may access through such third party applications are the sole responsibility of the person from which they originated and that neither Google nor Volvo Cars is liable for any loss or damage that you may experience as a result of the use or access of any of those third party applications, data, content, or resources. 7.2 You should be aware the data, content, and resources presented to you through such a third party application may be protected by intellectual property rights which are owned by the providers (or by other persons or companies on their behalf). You may not modify, rent, lease, loan, sell, distribute or create derivative works based on these data, content, or resources (either in whole or in part) unless you have been specifically given permission to do so by the relevant owners. 7.3 You acknowledge that your use of such third party applications, data, content, or resources may be subject to separate terms between you and the relevant third party. 8. Using Google APIs 8.1 Google APIs 8.1.1 If you use any API to retrieve data from Google, you acknowledge that the data may be protected by intellectual property rights which are owned by Google or those parties that provide the data (or by other persons or companies on their behalf). Your use of any such API may be subject to additional Terms of Service. You may not modify, rent, lease, loan, sell, distribute or create derivative works based on this data (either in whole or in part) unless allowed by the relevant Terms of Service. 8.1.2 If you use any API to retrieve a user’s data from Google, you acknowledge and agree that you shall retrieve data only with the user’s explicit consent and only when, and for the limited purposes for which, the user has given you permission to do so. 9. Terminating the License Agreement 9.1 The License Agreement will continue to apply until terminated by either you or Licensor as set out below. 9.2 If you want to terminate the License Agreement, you may do so by ceasing your use of the Emulator and any relevant developer credentials. 9.3 Google and/or Volvo Cars may at any time, terminate the License Agreement, with or without cause, upon notice to you. 9.4 The License Agreement will automatically terminate without notice or other action when Licensor ceases to provide the Emulator or certain parts of the Emulator to users in the country in which you are resident or from which you use the service. 9.5 When the License Agreement is terminated, the license granted to you in the License Agreement will terminate, you will immediately cease all use of the Emulator, and the provisions of paragraphs 10, 11, 12 and 14 shall survive indefinitely. 10. DISCLAIMERS 10.1 YOU EXPRESSLY UNDERSTAND AND AGREE THAT YOUR USE OF THE EMULATOR IS AT YOUR SOLE RISK AND THAT THE EMULATOR IS PROVIDED "AS IS" AND "AS AVAILABLE" WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND FROM VOLVO CARS OR GOOGLE. 10.2 YOUR USE OF THE EMULATOR AND ANY MATERIAL DOWNLOADED OR OTHERWISE OBTAINED THROUGH THE USE OF THE EMULATOR IS AT YOUR OWN DISCRETION AND RISK AND YOU ARE SOLELY RESPONSIBLE FOR ANY DAMAGE TO YOUR COMPUTER SYSTEM OR OTHER DEVICE OR LOSS OF DATA THAT RESULTS FROM SUCH USE. WITHOUT LIMITING THE FOREGOING, YOU UNDERSTAND THAT THE EMULATOR IS NOT A STABLE RELEASE AND MAY CONTAIN ERRORS, DEFECTS AND SECURITY VULNERABILITIES THAT CAN RESULT IN SIGNIFICANT DAMAGE, INCLUDING THE COMPLETE, IRRECOVERABLE LOSS OF USE OF YOUR COMPUTER SYSTEM OR OTHER DEVICE. 10.3 VOLVO CARS AND GOOGLE FURTHER EXPRESSLY DISCLAIMS ALL WARRANTIES AND CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, WHETHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES AND CONDITIONS OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NON-INFRINGEMENT. 11. LIMITATION OF LIABILITY 11.1 YOU EXPRESSLY UNDERSTAND AND AGREE THAT GOOGLE AND/OR VOLVO CARS, NOT EITHER OF GOOGLE OR VOLVO CARS’ SUBSIDIARIES AND AFFILIATES, AND ITS LICENSORS SHALL BE LIABLE TO YOU UNDER ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, CONSEQUENTIAL OR EXEMPLARY DAMAGES THAT MAY BE INCURRED BY YOU, INCLUDING ANY LOSS OF DATA, WHETHER OR NOT GOOGLE AND/OR VOLVO CARS OR EITHER OF GOOGLE OR VOLVO CARS’ REPRESENTATIVES HAVE BEEN ADVISED OF OR SHOULD HAVE BEEN AWARE OF THE POSSIBILITY OF ANY SUCH LOSSES ARISING. 12. Indemnification 12.1 To the maximum extent permitted by law, you agree to defend, indemnify and hold harmless Google, its affiliates and their respective directors, officers, employees and agents and Volvo Cars, its affiliates and their respective directors, officers, employees and agents from and against any and all claims, actions, suits or proceedings, as well as any and all losses, liabilities, damages, costs and expenses (including reasonable attorneys’ fees) arising out of or accruing from (a) your use of the Emulator, (b) any application you develop on the Emulator that infringes any Intellectual Property Rights of any person or defames any person or violates their rights of publicity or privacy, and (c) any non-compliance by you of the License Agreement. 13. Changes to the License Agreement 13.1 Licensor may make changes to the License Agreement as it distributes new versions of the Emulator. When these changes are made, Licensor will make a new version of the License Agreement available on the website where the Emulator is made available. 14. General Legal Terms 14.1 The License Agreement constitutes the whole legal agreement between you and Licensor and governs your use of the Emulator (excluding any services which Google and/or Volvo Cars may provide to you under a separate written agreement), and completely replaces any prior agreements between you and Licensor in relation to the Emulator. 14.2 You agree that if Licensor does not exercise or enforce any legal right or remedy which is contained in the License Agreement (or which Licensor has the benefit of under any applicable law), this will not be taken to be a formal waiver of Licensor’s rights and that those rights or remedies will still be available to Licensor. 14.3 If any court of law, having the jurisdiction to decide on this matter, rules that any provision of the License Agreement is invalid, then that provision will be removed from the License Agreement without affecting the rest of the License Agreement. The remaining provisions of the License Agreement will continue to be valid and enforceable. 14.4 You acknowledge and agree that each member of the group of companies of which Volvo Cars and Google is each the parent shall be third party beneficiaries to the License Agreement and that such other companies shall be entitled to directly enforce, and rely upon, any provision of the License Agreement that confers a benefit on (or rights in favor of) them. Other than this, no other person or company shall be third party beneficiaries to the License Agreement. 14.5 EXPORT RESTRICTIONS. THE EMULATOR IS SUBJECT TO UNITED STATES EXPORT LAWS AND REGULATIONS. YOU MUST COMPLY WITH ALL DOMESTIC AND INTERNATIONAL EXPORT LAWS AND REGULATIONS THAT APPLY TO THE EMULATOR. THESE LAWS INCLUDE RESTRICTIONS ON DESTINATIONS, END USERS AND END USE. 14.6 The License Agreement may not be assigned or transferred by you without the prior written approval of Licensor, and any attempted assignment without such approval will be void. You shall not delegate your responsibilities or obligations under the License Agreement without the prior written approval of Licensor. 14.7 The License Agreement, and your relationship with Licensor under the License Agreement, shall be governed by the laws of the State of California without regard to its conflict of laws provisions. You and Licensor agree to submit to the exclusive jurisdiction of the courts located within the county of Santa Clara, California to resolve any legal matter arising from the License Agreement. Notwithstanding this, you agree that Licensor shall still be allowed to apply for injunctive remedies (or an equivalent type of urgent legal relief) in any jurisdiction. </license>
	<license id="gm-sdk-license" type="text">Conditions THESE TERMS GOVERN YOUR USE OF THE GM SOFTWARE AND ARE LEGALLY BINDING BETWEEN YOU AND GM Developer Agreement Last Modified - December 2021 This Developer Agreement (“Agreement”) is between You (as defined in Section 1.2) and General Motors Holdings LLC and its affiliates (“GM” or “we” or “us”). Purpose You would like to contribute to the number of software applications available for download to a GM Connected Device (as defined below) and, in doing so, You desire to use the GM Software (as defined below) to develop one or more Applications (as defined below). GM is willing to grant You a limited, non-exclusive license to use the GM Software to develop and test Your Applications under the terms and conditions set forth in this Agreement. In general, if You develop an Application in accordance with this Agreement and that Application meets GM’s standards as set forth in this Agreement, its, attachments, exhibits, schedules and in any other documentation expressly referred to in this Agreement, You may submit Your Application to GM for GM to consider distributing to GM Connected Devices via the AppShop (as defined below) or otherwise. If approved by GM, Your Application may be, but is not required to be, distributed by or on behalf of GM or through one or more of the following methods: (1) through the AppShop, (2) included in firmware update to a GM Connected Device, (3) as embedded software in a GM Connected Device, including but not limited to, installed on a vehicle for sale, provided during the provision of warranty services and repairs or provided for aftermarket sales; or (4) any similar means of distribution via any medium or channel, whether now known or developed in the future. 1. Accepting this Agreement; Definitions 1.1 Acceptance By downloading or using the GM Software You signify Your acceptance of and agreement with the terms of this Agreement. When You accept the terms of this Agreement, You accept on behalf of Yourself, and Your company, Your organization, or Your institution as its legally authorized representative. If You do not agree with any term of this Agreement, do not download or use the GM software. 1.2 Definitions This Agreement contains terms that are capitalized, and those terms have the following meanings: "Agreement" means this Developer Agreement and license for the GM Software, including any and all attachments, exhibits, schedules and other documentation expressly referred to herein and any permitted amendments to any of the foregoing. "applicable law(s)" means, when used, all laws applicable to the development, delivery and use of Your Application, wherever in the world it is made available for use. "Application" means a program that You developed, which complies with this Agreement and the Documentation, for use with a GM Connected Device, including all updates, enhancements, fixes, releases and versions of the program. “AppShop" means a system or means of distributing applications, including through Google Play Store or an online site owned or controlled by GM where GM intends to make Applications available to customers for their GM Connected Devices. "AppShop Requirements" means all standards, criteria, procedures, including but not limited to GM’s certificate procedure, and requirements as set forth in this Agreement or the Documentation as GM may modify from time to time. "Authorized Users" means You (if you are acting in Your individual capacity) or Your employees, officers, directors, contractors, staffs, representatives and agents (if You are acting as a representative of Your entity, organization or institution) who need to know or use the GM Software for the development and testing of Applications and who, in the case of contractors, representatives and agents, with whom You have a written and binding agreement that requires, or in the case of employees, to whom You have explained the obligations of, protecting the confidentiality of the GM Software, the Documentation and all other information and documentation that we make available to You. "Documentation" means any technical documents, specifications, procedures, guidelines or standards, including the GM HMI guidelines and GM Technical Guidelines for GM Infotainment Application Developers, that GM may make available to You in connection with the GM Software, the AppShop or Applications. “End User” means the person using a GM Connected Device and one or more Applications. “End User Data” means information about an End User, whether personally identifiable or not, including information about driver behavior, End User characteristics, activities, preferences and interests, and also including information that can be used, together with other information or data, to personally identify an End User. End User Data includes any vehicle ID, GM Connected Device ID, or other device ID or similar identifier, that is or can be associated with an End User or End User activity. End User Data includes Vehicle Data. "GM API(s)" means the Application Programming Interface(s) that GM specifies in the Documentation and in the GM Software. “GM Connected Device” means a device produced by GM, for GM, or as authorized by GM that is capable of receiving Applications created using the GM Software. “GM Link Protocol” means GM’s proprietary protocol for interfacing with a GM Connected Device through an external wired or wireless connection. “GM Representatives” includes its contractors, suppliers, affiliates, third party service providers and any other person GM appoints to act on its behalf and the employees, officers and directors of the foregoing. "GM Software" collectively means the SDK software, associated files, applications, sample code, simulator, emulator, tools, libraries, APIs, data (including End User Data and Vehicle Data), files, and materials and documentation, together with any and all pre-release versions, corrections, improvements, updates and releases to any of the foregoing that GM makes available or discloses to You. “SDK” means the GM software developer’s kit provided by GM to develop an Application for use with a GM Connected Device. “Mobile Marketing Association's Privacy Policy Framework” means the latest version and any continuing updates, of the Mobile Marketing Association’s Privacy Policy Framework as developed by the Mobile Marketing Association. “Open Source License” means a software license that includes, but is not limited to, terms that: (a) permit distribution/redistribution of the software by others without royalty or fee; (b) allows for such distribution/redistribution to include source code and compiled code; (c) permits modifications, compilations, and derived works be created from the software and be distributed under the same terms as the original software; or (d) attach to the software and applies to all persons, entities, groups, organizations and institutions (the “Recipients”) to whom the software is distributed or who redistribute the software without the need for the Recipients to execute or otherwise acquire an additional license. "Open Source Software" means software, including source code and compiled code, made available to others under the terms of an Open Source License. Open Source Software may include Android system files, packaged APIs, and library files provided by Google under the Android Open Source Project, located at: source.android.com. “Standard End User License” means the standard end user license agreement for customers, a copy of which (for the U.S.) included as Exhibit A to this Agreement. “Term” has the meaning set forth in Section 14 of this Agreement. "You" is sometimes referred to as “Your” and “Licensee” in this Agreement and refers to you individually or the entity, organization or institution who You acted on behalf of in entering this Agreement. “Vehicle Data” means information about the vehicle, including its operation, performance, settings, location and servicing, and information about the type of vehicle. 2. Use and Restrictions on GM Software and Documentation 2.1 License Subject to the terms and conditions of this Agreement, GM hereby grants You during the Term of this Agreement, for the limited purpose of meeting AppShop Requirements, a nonexclusive, limited, revocable, non-sublicensable, non-transferable and royalty-free license to do the following with GM Software and Documentation: (i) have access to, install, use, and operate the GM Software on a limited number of computers owned and controlled by You as appropriate for Authorized Users to use solely in Your internal development and testing of Applications to meet the AppShop Requirements for use exclusively on GM Connected Devices; (ii) make a limited number of copies of the Documentation for distribution solely to Your Authorized Users to use solely in Your internal development and testing of Applications meeting the AppShop Requirements; and (iii) to use and incorporate elements of the GM Software into the Application pursuant to the Documentation and to distribute such elements as incorporated into the Application, as necessary and intended by GM to provide for operation of the Application on GM Connected Devices. To the extent that Open Source Software files are included in the GM Software, Your rights in those files and the Open Source Software are specified in the documentation provided with those files or as GM makes available to You. You acknowledge that You may be required to separately consent to additional terms in the documentation provided with Open Source Software files and other third party software and that Your use of those files may be conditioned upon compliance with those additional terms. There are no implied rights granted to You in this Agreement. 2.2 Pre-Release GM Software GM may provide You GM Software in pre-release form for Your review, evaluation and so You can provide feedback to GM (“Pre-release Software”). You agree not to rely on Pre-release Software for final release of Applications to GM. Since Pre-release Software may include functionality that GM has not yet released or decided to release, You agree not to discuss the capabilities of the Pre-release Software or the functionalities of Applications developed with Prerelease Software. You also acknowledge that Pre-release Software may not be bug-free and may result in loss of data that is not backed-up and may require additional maintenance to Your systems. 2.3 Notices Kept on Copies On each copy of GM Software and Documentation used under this Agreement, You agree to keep any copyright notice, disclaimer of warranty, notices that refer to this Agreement, and any other provided notices in their full and original form without any modifications or additions. 2.4 Ownership of GM Software and Documentation (a) GM Software and Documentation. GM or its licensors retain(s) all rights, title, and interest, including all intellectual property and proprietary rights, in and to the GM Software and Documentation that GM may make available to You under this Agreement. You agree that the GM Software and Documentation is only licensed and not sold to You. You agree not to make any claim of ownership or interest in the GM Software or Documentation and to notify GM if anyone makes such a claim to You or You become aware of a claim of ownership or interest in the GM Software or Documentation. (b) Open Source Software. To the extent that Open Source Software files are included in the GM Software, ownership rights in such Open Source Software are specified in such files and the documentation provided with those files. (c) Application. Nothing in this Agreement transfers ownership of any right, title or interest, including any intellectual property or other proprietary rights, from You (or your licensors) to GM in Your Application. 2.5 Restrictions on Use of GM Software and Documentation As a condition of the license and rights granted in this Agreement, including Section 2.1, you agree to each of the following: (a) You agree to use the GM Software and Documentation only for the purposes expressly set forth in this Agreement. (b) You will not copy, distribute or modify any of the GM Software or Documentation, except as expressly set forth in Section 2.1. (c) You agree not to make any derivatives of the GM Software and that, except as expressly provided with respect to certain Open Source Software files, a source code version of the GM Software is not licensed hereunder and shall not be provided to You. (d) Your rights under this Agreement are restricted solely to You and may not be assigned, sublicensed, sold, disposed of, encumbered, or mortgaged. (e) You agree to abide by and will not circumvent any security means or access control technology included with the GM Software and Documentation. (f) You also agree that You shall not reverse engineer, disassemble or decompile any of the GM Software or take any action to obtain the source code of the GM Software. (g) You agree not to rent, lease, re-sell, lend, upload to or host on any website or server, sell, redistribute, or sublicense the GM Software or Documentation, in whole or in part, or to enable others to do so. (h) You may not use the GM Software or the Documentation for any purpose not expressly permitted by this Agreement. (i) You will not use the GM Software or Documentation to trespass upon, misappropriate, gain unauthorized access to, or engage in any similar activity with respect to, any computer or system of GM or any other person or entity. (j) You will not use the GM Software or Documentation to disable, defeat the security of, interfere with the security of, remove the digital signature of, or disable the digital rights management, verification or authentication systems of any computer or system of GM or any other person or entity. (k) You will only use the GM Software and Documentation in accordance with all applicable laws and regulations. You will not use the GM Software or Documentation for any unlawful or illegal activity, nor to develop any Application which would commit or facilitate the commission of a crime, or other tortious, unlawful or illegal act. (l) You will not use the GM, GMC, or General Motors name, any GM trademark, logo or brand or any variation, translation or transliteration thereof in any manner, whether or alone or with any additional wording or design, not expressly authorized by GM in writing. 2.6 Updates; No GM Support or Maintenance of GM Software GM may update, modify, extend, enhance, re-release and improve the GM Software and Documentation from time to time at GM’s sole discretion. GM is not obligated to provide You with the GM Software and Documentation or any of the updates, modifications, extensions, enhancements, re-releases and improvements to the GM Software or Documentation. You agree that GM is not obligated to provide any maintenance or support, technical or otherwise, to You or any End User under this Agreement or any other form of obligation. You agree that this Agreement shall govern any of the updates, modifications, extensions, enhancements, rereleases and improvements to the GM Software and Documentation that GM may make available to You. 2.7 AppShop, GM Software and Documentation Availability. You agree that GM may discontinue owning or operating the AppShop or providing the GM Software and Documentation at any time without any notice or liability to you. 3. Your Representations and Obligations 3.1 General You certify to GM and agree that: (a) You have the right and authority to enter into this Agreement on Your own behalf and, if applicable, on behalf of Your company, organization or institution and that You have the right and authority to legally bind Your company, organization or institution to the terms and obligations of this Agreement; (b) You are at least 18 years of age (or the age of full legal capacity in your location); (c) You will provide GM only with true, complete and accurate information and will keep that information up to date; (d) You will monitor Your use of the GM Software and Documentation and keep Yourself and Your Authorized Users in full compliance with the requirements of this Agreement; (e) You will be responsible for all of Your costs and expenses, including losses and liabilities, that You incur in connection with any of Your use of the GM Software and Documentation, any Application and any activities that You undertake to develop any Application in connection with this Agreement in any way; (f) You agree that You own the necessary rights or have authority to grant the rights that You provide to GM under this Agreement; (g) Your agreement to these terms does not in any way violate any of Your existing obligations; (h) Your Application will operate and perform the functionality in the manner as you describe to GM and your disclosure to GM will include all functionality of Your Application. Any documentation distributed with or in Your Application and any advertisements or marketing You offer for Your Application shall accurately describe the operation and functionality and shall not make any false or misleading statements in that regard, and shall otherwise comply with the AppShop Requirements and Documentation. (i) You will only request the End User Data from GM that You require to develop and test Your Applications to meet the AppShop Requirements, and GM may provide the End User Data and Vehicle Data in its sole discretion; (j) Your Application and all information and any other content provided or used with or through Your Application, whether provided directly or indirectly to GM or to any GM Connected Device, do not and will not, under all applicable laws, violate, misappropriate, or infringe any GM or third party copyrights, trademarks, rights of privacy and publicity, trade secrets, patents, or other proprietary or legal rights (e.g. musical composition or performance rights, video rights, photography or image rights, logo rights, third party data rights, etc., for content and materials that may be included in Your Application); (k) As to Your Application and any and all associated Application commands and code, You and not GM or GM Representatives are the “Information Content Provider” for the Application, its Codes and Commands. (l) GM has adopted and implemented a policy in accordance with the Digital Millennium Copyright Act, 17 USC 512 and similar laws in other jurisdictions, and such policy is available at the AppShop or on the GM website and You will cooperate with GM in implementing its policy, as requested. 4. Requirements for Your Applications You agree that if You choose to submit any Application(s) for distribution by GM, Your Applications will meet all of GM’s AppShop Requirements, including, but not limited to, the following: 4.1 Your Applications must use only GM’s designated APIs set forth in the Documentation that we make available to You and only in the manner specified in the Documentation. Your Application must not call within the GM Connected Device (a) any private APIs, or (b) any other APIs not included and authorized in the Documentation that we make available to You. Your Application also must not install or attempt to install any code that includes additional APIs that may be called within the GM Connected Device. 4.2 Your Applications must comply with GM’s HMI (Human Machine Interface) standards provided in the Documentation. 4.3 You agree that You and Your Application will comply at all times with the AppShop Requirements and all applicable local, state and federal laws and any governmental rules or regulations in the places where End Users of Your Application are ordinarily resident. 4.4 End User Data Usage and Privacy (a) Your Applications must include a privacy statement that: i. complies with all applicable laws, regulations, and industry standards in the place where End Users of Your Application are ordinarily resident, including, but not limited to, the Mobile Marketing Association’s Privacy Policy Framework, App Privacy Guidelines as issued by the Future of Privacy Forum and the Center for Democracy and Technology; or similar industry standards now or subsequently developed, including any final multi-stakeholder guidance resulting from the NTIA app multi-stakeholder process; ii. clearly and completely describes the type of End User Data collected by the Application (whether provided directly by End Users or collected Automatically) and how and for what purposes that data will be used and, if applicable, shared, and with whom; iii. clearly describes where the End User Data will be geographically stored (e.g. United States, European Union, Canada, Other); iv. clearly and completely describes any controls that End Users have over the use and sharing of End User Data; v. is conspicuously disclosed to the End User prior to the deployment of Your Application’s functionality (i.e., prior to download or activation); vi. forms part of a mechanism for getting express opt-in consent from the End User to Your use of End User Data; vii. is accessible from within Your Application; and viii. describes how an End User can find or request or obtain a hard copy or printable electronic version of the privacy statement through a website or other means. Any retroactive (i.e., applicable to End User Data previously collected under a privacy statement), material changes to privacy practices must be added to an amended privacy statement, must be separately communicated to End Users independent of the privacy statement, and You must obtain, separate from other disclosures, End Users’ express, opt-in permission prior to the privacy statement changes being effective. (b) Your Applications will not collect or transmit any form of End User Data except as directly relevant to the End User’s use of the Application, to serve advertising, or as otherwise specifically allowed in the Documentation. (c) You also agree that You and Your Application will, consistent with Section 4.3, comply at all times with the AppShop Requirements and all applicable local, state and federal laws and any governmental rules or regulations applicable in the place Your End Users are ordinarily resident, including those specifically relevant to privacy, collection of location data and to the installation of a computer program on another person’s computer, the altering of transmission data, and the sending of electronic messages. This compliance includes, but is not limited to: (i) You or Your Application collecting, accessing, transmitting, sharing, or processing of any data, including, but not limited to End User Data and location data, device features such as a phone or camera, or other End User communications or content; (ii) You or Your Application causing any computer program to be installed or updated or to send any electronic message; or (iii) You or Your Application causing the transmission of any data in an electronic message to be altered. (d) Your Application will not collect, transmit, use or share End User Data, including any disclosure of such data to GM or GM Representatives, without prior consent that is solicited and obtained in compliance with all applicable laws, regulations, and industry standards applicable in the place Your End Users are ordinarily resident. (e) If Your Application provides any type of location-based route or guidance function or otherwise collects geo-location data, Your Application will: (i) before providing the service or function, alert End Users, separate from the privacy statement and independent of other disclosures, that location data will be collected and obtain End Users clear, express opt-in permission prior to collection; and (ii) include a conspicuous and contemporaneous visual indicator that geolocation tracking is enabled. (f) If Your Application provides any (i) geo-tagging; (ii) auto-sharing with third party platforms other than GM (also known as frictionless sharing); or (iii) collects any End User content from the GM Connected Device or Vehicle such as contacts, photos, videos or messages; Your Application will, before providing such service or function, clearly alert End Users, separate from the privacy statement and independent of other disclosures, of the specific activity and content that will be collected and obtain End Users’ clear, express opt-in permission prior to such collection and sharing. (g) If consent is not obtained from an End User for any activity addressed in (d) – (f) above, then Your Application must not commence End User Data collection, transmission, use or sharing functions and if consent previously obtained is revoked by an End User, Your Application must disable the service or immediately terminate End User Data collection, transmission, use or sharing functions. (h) You will retain any End User Data You receive from GM only for so long as You reasonably require it for the purpose of developing and testing of Your Applications to meet the AppShop Requirements, but in any event, no longer than as permitted in accordance with applicable laws, regulations, and industry standards. Additionally, You will delete all End User Data You receive from GM if the End User or GM asks you to do so. You will provide an easily accessible mechanism for End Users to make such a request. GM may require You to delete End User Data You receive from GM if You violate any provision of this Agreement or otherwise within its sole discretion. If Your Application is not submitted to or accepted by GM, or if GM removes Your Application from the AppShop, You must delete all End User Data You have received from GM unless You have received explicit consent from the End User to retain their End User Data. 4.5 Your Application will not link to or access (or cause a link or access to) any service or website in a manner that will violate the terms and conditions of that service or website. You agree that if Your Application links to or accesses any service or website, You will abide by, and Your Application will comply with, the terms and conditions of that service or website. 4.6 If Your Application provides any type of location-based route or guidance function, Your Application will, each time before providing the service or function, provide a notice as follows: CAUTION: LOCATION DATA MAY NOT BE ACCURATE, USE THIS APPLICATION AT YOUR OWN SOLE RISK. 4.7 Your Application must not use resources of the GM Connected Device in a manner that would interfere with (a) the operation of the GM Connected Device or (b) any system alerts, warnings, displays or other functions, including those provided by GM, the GM Connected Device, vehicle or vehicle component. 4.8 Your Application will only include, use, be derived from or based on, link to or provide media content (e.g., video, photographs, artwork, audio-visual materials, social media content, maps) or other information and materials (e.g., news reports, sports scores, financial data, ratings and reviews) if You: (a) have complete and sole ownership thereof with unrestricted rights, or (b) have permission or rights pursuant to a written agreement to reproduce, create derivative works, display, perform and distribute the media content, information or materials, as applicable, and to allow others (through multiple tiers of sublicensing) to reproduce, display, perform and distribute the content as included in Your Application to End Users for installation and use by End Users without any payment of any fees, royalties or any other form of monies by GM or End Users. This Section does not extend to third party software, which is covered by Sections 4.10 and 4.11. 4.9 Your Application must not contain, link to, access, provide or download any obscene or pornographic material or any material that is defamatory. The following applies to all Applications except in the provision of news services: Your Application must not contain, link to, access, provide or download any offensive or defamatory content or materials of any kind or any content or materials that may harm GM (including but not limited to GM and each of GM’s affiliate’s name, reputation or good standing in the community) or that End Users may find objectionable. 4.10 Your Application will only include, use, be derived from or based on, link to or provide access to third party software that You have permission or rights pursuant to a written agreement to use, make, have made, reproduce, modify, distribute, display, and perform and to allow others to exercise such rights through multiple tiers of sublicensing without any payment of any fees, royalties or any other form of monies by GM or End Users. In relation to Your Application(s), it is You, and not GM, that is the distributor of the Application. You will be responsible for compliance with any direct and indirect obligations, including obligations related to distribution, manufacture, use, reproduction, modification, display, performance, sublicensing, or transfer associated in any way with any Open Source Software or third party software, that is used with or forms any part of Your Application. Your obligations include, but are not limited to, compliance with all applicable licenses, copyrights, and any other legal obligations associated with the Open Source Software or third party software that is used with or included in Your Application and with the distribution manufacture, use, reproduction, modification, display, performance, sublicensing, transfer or sale of Your Application and products containing Your Application. 4.11 Your Application must not include, use, be derived from or based on, access or link to any Open Source Software or third party software that would require distribution or disclosure of any GM Software, other than those components provided by GM to You as Open Source Software, or distribution or disclosure of any Documentation, APIs, or any other proprietary information of GM or any other party. 4.12 You will obtain and maintain all necessary rights, clearances, consents, and licenses and pay all use, redistribution and reuse fees associated with Your Application, including, using, providing or linking to any third party content, information, materials or software through Your Application. You expressly acknowledge that the foregoing includes an obligation to obtain and maintain rights, clearances, consents, and licenses for, and pay all license, use, redistribution and reuse fees applicable in any place where an End User of Your Application is ordinarily resident. 4.13 Your Application must not include any superfluous software, including but not limited to any superfluous Open Source Software, that is not necessary for the Application to perform its intended function. 4.14 Your Application must not include any form of Open Source Software or third party software for which payment by GM or any End User is required for the distribution or use. Your Application must not use any software or content, including but not limited to any Open Source Software having an Open Source License, which imposes obligations that contradict in any way the terms of this Agreement or the AppShop Requirements. 4.15 If Your Application interfaces the GM Connected Device with any other device, You will use only the GM Link Protocol and You and the use and operation of Your Application will at all times abide by all of GM’s policies and procedures related to the GM Link Protocol. 4.16 Your Application must not implement voice over IP functionality. 4.17 Your Application must not use excessive cellular network data or exceed cellular network data expectations of GM or the user. 4.18 Your Application must post a high data usage warning and obtain user consent before streaming media or any other content that may lead to excess data charges for a user. 4.19 You may not push any information or functionality to Your Application. Streaming audio for a program requested by a user and advertisements that meet the AppShop Requirements are not considered pushed information or functionality under this Section. 4.20 Your agreement to these terms does not obligate GM to provide or offer to You any service or other agreement, even if GM offers that agreement or service to others or in other locations. 4.21 You understand and agree that GM provides its business through its employees, contractors, suppliers, affiliates, and third party service providers and that none of GM's employees, suppliers, affiliates and third party service providers have any liability to You arising out of this Agreement. 4.22 You understand and agree that GM has the right to change the AppShop, the AppShop Requirements, procedures, this Agreement, any standards and policies relating to any of the foregoing, and any services that GM provides at any time without any notice or liability to You. 4.23 You understand and agree that GM has the right to remove Your Application from the AppShop at any time without any notice or liability to You. You also understand that GM has the right to remove Your Application, advise users to remove Your Application, and to advise any service provider to remove Your Application from any GM Connected Device at any time without any notice or liability to You. While GM may remove any Application in its sole discretion without a specified reason, the following is a list of examples why GM might take one of these actions: (a) Your Application does not meet the AppShop Requirements; (b) Your Application does not function properly; (c) You failed to meet any of Your representations or obligations under this Agreement; (d) Your Application has a virus or bug; (e) Your Application disrupts operation of a GM Connected Device or any other device or system; (f) repairs or replacement is needed of a GM Connected Device; (g) regulation, law or order of a court; (h) this Agreement is terminated; (i) the digital certificate on Your Application expires; or (j) Your Application accesses a system, computer, or application program interface without authorization. 4.24 The AppShop may allow users to comment on and rate Applications. You agree to not attempt to manipulate ratings for Your Application or any other Application, and You may not rate Your own Application. You may contact GM if You have any questions or concerns regarding these ratings 4.25 If You discover that Your Application violates the terms of this Agreement, You must immediately notify GM and, without limiting any other rights or remedies of GM, cooperate with GM as requested to address such violation. 4.26. Application Data Security. (a) Your Application must not contain any hidden files, any automatically replicating, transmitting or activating computer program, any virus, Trojan horse, worm (or other malicious computer program), or any program that limits normal operation of the GM Connected Device or any other GM system or other software or services provided through the GM Connected Device or any other GM system. (b) Your Application will implement state of the art security to prevent unauthorized access or use by others of the Application and to prevent unauthorized access to or use of any system, network, data or other information and materials 5. AppShop Requirements Review 5.1 When You believe that Your Application is complete and ready for distribution, You may submit Your Application to GM in object code and source code formats. 5.2 You will not submit for distribution any Application that is a beta, demo, trial or test version of Your Application. 5.3 You represent and warrant that Your Application, upon submission to GM, will comply with this Agreement, the AppShop Requirements, and the Documentation. You also represent and warrant that Your Application does not generate any error when executed in the emulator included in the SDK. 5.4 You grant to GM and GM Representatives the right to perform any and all review and testing of Your Application on an ongoing basis as GM sees fit for compliance with the AppShop Requirements (including data security testing for security vulnerabilities), including the right to copy, use, display, and modify the source code and object code of Your Application and any media, software and other materials within, linked to, used with or downloaded to or through Your Application. 5.5 When You submit Your Application to GM, You will describe all functionality of Your Application and will not hide any functionality of Your Application from GM. You will describe all connections that Your Application makes and all locations to which Your Application connects. 5.6 If Your Application connects to any other device, You will also provide to GM one example of each type of device to which Your Application connects and describe all types of connections to each of the devices. 5.7 Prior to the release of Your Application through the AppShop, If GM requests any changes to Your Application, its functionality, or content within or available through Your Application, You will make those changes and re-submit Your Application to GM as requested by GM. 5.8 You agree that all updates, fixes, upgrades, enhancements, modifications and extensions of Your Application must be submitted to GM in the same manner as a new Application and in full accordance with the AppShop Requirements and is subject to GM’s review. GM does not guarantee that it will distribute any updates, fixes, upgrades, enhancements, modifications or extensions of Your Application that You submit to GM. 5.9 If Your Application is released through the AppShop, and GM requests any changes to Your Application, its functionality, or content within or available through Your Application, You will make those changes and re-submit Your Application to GM. 5.10 GM may in its sole discretion accept or reject Your Application for any or no reason and without any notification or liability to You. 5.11 GM may in its sole discretion accept Your Application for distribution by you through any one or more of the following: (a) the AppShop; (b) firmware update to a GM Connected Device; (c) as embedded software in a GM Connected Device, including but not limited to, installed on a vehicle for sale, provided during the provision of warranty services and repairs or provided for aftermarket sales; or (d) any similar means of distribution via any medium or channel whether now known or developed in the future. You agree that if GM determines that Your Application is to be distributed, GM will use its sole discretion to determine the manner of distribution by you of Your Application. 5.12 You understand that Your Application will be distributed in any manner described in this Agreement with a digital certificate meeting GM’s standards as GM determines from time to time and You grant GM and GM Representatives the right to take all action with regard to Your Application to implement the digital certificate and any of GM’s distribution methods. 5.13 You understand and You give GM and GM Representatives the express permission to use Your name, trademark, logo and brand to identify and market Your Application worldwide in connection with the distribution and marketing of Your Application, including on any website for the AppShop. No other rights to your trademark, logo or brand are transferred to GM under this Agreement. 5.14 Your expressly acknowledge that You are not relying on GM in any way arising out of the review conducted pursuant to this Section 5 (or otherwise). You acknowledge that Your compliance with this Agreement, the AppShop Requirements, and the Documentation and all applicable laws is entirely Your responsibility. 6. Delivery of Application and Licenses to GM 6.1 If GM clears Your Application for distribution, You appoint GM and GM Representatives as Your agent to distribute Your Application and to take all actions necessary with regard to Your Application to distribute Your Application in any and all of the manners described in this Agreement and according to the terms of this Agreement and the AppShop Requirements. If distribution of Your Application is not free of charge, You and GM will work together to resolve the terms associated with any such charges, including revenue sharing, payment terms, and other related terms. 6.2 If GM clears Your Application for distribution, You hereby grant to GM and GM Representatives an irrevocable, non-exclusive, royalty-free, transferable right and license worldwide to use Your Application in source code and object code and to distribute your Application in object code as set forth in Section 5.11; this use includes the right to make, have made, host, copy, modify, create derivative works, improve, expand, update, make, display, perform and sublicense in any form or medium, whether now known or hereafter developed, Your Application in order to make it available to End Users using the branding provided by you or otherwise resolved in consultation with you. Other than any revenue sharing that is separately agreed by GM and You, GM will not be responsible for making any payment to you for the activities licensed in this Section. 6.3 You acknowledge and agree that the foregoing rights and licenses extend to any third party media contact, information materials or third party software that Your Application include, use, are derived from or based on, link to or provide access to. 7. No Other Distribution by You Except for distribution via GM as contemplated by this Agreement, You agree not to, and not to permit or enable others to, distribute or otherwise provide to any third parties any version of Your Application (or any other software) that You develop using the GM Software. This restriction will not apply to any version of Your Application (or any other software) that is not created, developed, modified or adapted using the GM Software. 8. Application Maintenance and Support 8.1 You shall be solely responsible to provide any and all documentation, user manuals or guides and all customer support for Your Application. 8.2 You agree and acknowledge that it is Your responsibility to ensure that Your Application including any installation of it, or any upgrades or updates, on any GM Connected Device, complies will all laws in any country in or from which it may be used, installed, upgraded, or updated. GM’s standard end user terms (the “GM Terms”) will apply to your relationship with End Users and create a contractual relationship between You and each End User of Your Application. The GM Terms are, subject to local legal requirements, consistent with the Standard End User License. If you, in your sole discretion, require additional terms to apply to End Users of your Application, then You may submit such additional terms for presentation to such End Users (“Your Additional Terms”). You will ensure that Your Additional Terms comply with the Documentation, comply with all applicable laws in all countries where the corresponding Application can be downloaded, installed, updated, or upgraded, are consistent with the GM Terms, and are consistent with the terms of this Agreement. If Your Additional Terms conflict with the GM Terms, then the GM Terms will govern. Without limiting the foregoing, the Application must describe the function and purpose of the Application, set out a valid mailing and email address for You, and obtain whatever consent may be required to allow for the installation of the Application on the GM Connected Device. You must also solicit and obtain whatever additional consent may be required to allow for the upgrade or update of the Application on the GM Connected Device. You must provide a resource to allow for the end user to print a copy of Your Additional Terms, if any. You appoint GM as Your agent to present the GM Terms and Your Additional Terms on behalf of You to the end user. Although GM facilitates Your licensing of the Application to the End User, GM has no responsibilities to You or the End User in relation to Your Application, except as otherwise expressly provided under this Agreement. Any end user license agreement for Your Application (including the GM Terms and Your Additional Terms) is binding solely between You and the End User. 8.3 You agree that GM and its subsidiaries are third party beneficiaries of any end user license agreement for Your Application and thus GM can enforce the end user license agreement against an End User of Your Application, provided that if the doctrine of third-party beneficiaries is found to not apply for any reason, the parties acknowledge and agree that while GM is not a party to the end user license agreement and has no obligations under the end user license agreement, You will be a trustee of GM for the limited purpose of holding in trust for GM the covenants in favor of GM. Accordingly, GM will be able to enforce such rights and promises in its own right (without being required to add You as a party to any proceedings for such enforcement). 9. Fees 9.1 GM will notify You through GM’s website in advance of execution, or if already executed, in advance of each calendar year, of any fees due by You in connection with exercising any of the rights or receiving any of the benefits provided to You under this Agreement. You agree to pay all fees due (if any) prior to submitting any Application to GM or within 30 days of the beginning of each calendar year, whichever is sooner. 10. Confidentiality and Security Breach Reporting 10.1 You agree to protect all Documentation and GM Software against unauthorized use, disclosure, publication or dissemination and, in doing so, exercise in no event less than a reasonable degree of care. Without limiting the foregoing, You agree to ensure the confidentiality of End User Data received from GM, GM Representatives or End Users via reasonable information security controls, such as encryption or similar means, or such other security controls as prescribed by applicable law. 10.2 Except as expressly authorized in this Agreement, You shall not use for Your own benefit or the benefit of any third party, or disclose, publish, release, transfer or otherwise provide access to or make available to any third party, any Documentation or GM Software, or End User Data or Vehicle Data provided by GM or any GM Representative, without GM’s prior written consent. You shall be responsible for any violation of the confidentiality obligations set forth herein by any party or person who receives the Documentation or GM Software from or through You. 10.3 Any information that GM makes available to the public without restriction or that is provided under the terms of a separate license as part of any Open Source Software that GM provides to You need not be treated as confidential under this Agreement. 10.4 As to (i) Documentation, GM Software, and End User Data that You receive from GM or (ii) where there may be an effect on a GM Connected Device, upon the occurrence of a security breach or suspected security breach, meaning actual or suspected unauthorized access to or effect upon the GM Connected Device or unauthorized use, disclosure, acquisition, or loss of any such information or material, You shall notify GM immediately, but in no event more than 24 hours, following Your learning of the incident, with full disclosure regarding all relevant known information. You shall update GM on an ongoing basis and cooperate fully with any related GM investigation, requests for information, or End User or other notices that GM may require of You. Because in such circumstances, time is of the essence, such notice shall occur as specified in the Documentation and not Section 16.5 11. Your Feedback and Submissions 11.1 GM is interested in receiving Your feedback regarding the GM Software, Documentation and AppShop and needs to review certain information from You as we describe in this Agreement and in the AppShop Requirements (“Submissions”). You grant to GM and GM Representatives an irrevocable, non-exclusive, transferable, royalty-free right and license worldwide to use Your Submissions; this use includes the right to copy, modify, create derivative works, improve, expand, update, make, distribute, display, perform and sublicense in connection with any GM Software, the AppShop and Documentation in any manner any in any form or medium, whether now known or hereafter developed, without any notification, payment or attribution to You. For the avoidance of doubt, Submissions do not include Your Applications. 11.2 Because many applications and potential applications may be similar to Your Applications and potential Applications, much of the information that we receive from You and others may be similar. Because of this, and to avoid any misunderstandings, You agree that Your submission to GM or any GM Representative of information and materials under this Agreement or in any way connected to the GM Software, Documentation or AppShop, including the Application and Submissions, creates no confidentiality obligation on the part of GM or any GM Representative in any way and You acknowledge that GM does not consider such information or materials confidential. Your information and material is being delivered voluntarily and without restriction, and GM is free to use and disclose any information and material that You provide in connection with this Agreement without any obligation, express or implied, to You. You also agree that GM has no obligation to return or destroy any information or materials that You provide to GM. Thus, You should retain a copy of any information or materials You submit to GM or any GM Representative. 12. No Restrictions Against Similar Applications You acknowledge that GM retains full right to acquire, and has no restrictions under this agreement against acquiring in any way or developing, alone or with others, any new or future service or application regardless of whether it is similar to or in any way the same as Your Application. 13. Indemnity You agree to indemnify GM and GM Representatives from and against any and all losses, damages, injuries (including death), causes of action, claims, penalties, interest, additional taxes, demands and expenses, including reasonable legal fees and expenses, of any kind or nature arising out or on account of, or resulting from, any claim or allegation of a third party or investigation by any Government entity: (i) arising out of failure to comply with this Agreement by You or Authorized Users; (ii) that Your Application, any activities by You or Authorized Users in connection with this Agreement, or any information or materials provided by or through You, Authorized Users or Your Application infringe upon or misappropriate the intellectual property or other proprietary rights of any third party; (iii) relating to any of Your duties or obligations to any of Your employees, contractors or agents (in all cases direct or indirect), through any agreement or otherwise; (iv) relating to the inaccuracy or untruthfulness of any representation or warranty that You made under this Agreement; (v) relating to any liability of GM or any GM Representative arising out of Your failure to comply with any relevant privacy, data protection, laws governing collection of location data, or similar legislation, regulation or any other law in any jurisdiction where Your Application may be used or accessed; (vi) relating to any action of You or anyone on Your behalf; (vii) relating to the operation or performance of Your Application, whether as You intended it or due to bug or other error; (viii) relating to Your failure to implement best practices in physical or data security controls; or (ix) relating to Your introduction of viruses into the AppShop or any computer network or data security breaches caused by You or Your Application. You shall also pay or reimburse GM, at its discretion, for any and all costs relating to a security breach, including forensic investigation costs, attorneys fees, notices to End Users or others, credit monitoring service costs for End Users, and any other related costs even absent a third party claim or allegation or Government entity investigation. 14. Term and Termination 14.1 This Agreement shall extend from the date of Your acceptance until terminated by You or GM in accordance with the terms of this Agreement (the “Term”). 14.2 GM may terminate this Agreement immediately if You: (i) breach any obligation of this Agreement or fail to comply with the AppShop Requirements; (ii) if any person or party acting by, through, for or in concert with You takes any action inconsistent with this Agreement or the AppShop Requirements; (iii) You file any lawsuit against GM; (iv) You engage in, encourage, or participate in any unlawful, deceitful or fraudulent conduct; (v) You become insolvent or file for bankruptcy or become subject to any similar proceeding; (vi) You fail to agree with new AppShop Requirements or modifications to this Agreement as we may make available to You. 14.3 Either Party may terminate this Agreement at any time upon thirty (30) days written notice to the other Party. 14.4 GM shall have no liability to You for termination of this Agreement. Upon termination, You shall stop using all GM Software, Documentation, End User Data provided by GM and Vehicle Data and return or destroy all copies of the GM Software, Documentation, End User Data provided by GM and Vehicle Data in Your possession (or the possession of any Authorized Users) or provided to any person by You (or any Authorized Users). You will provide a written certification of the destruction at GM’s request. Notwithstanding the foregoing, You must maintain all information and records (if any) that the AppShop Requirements identify that You maintain for the period (if any) set forth in the AppShop Requirements. 14.5 All of Your obligations related in any way to (a) confidentiality or indemnity, (b) Sections 4, 5, 6, 10, 13, 15, and 16, and (c) restrictions on use of any GM Software or Documentation in Your possession shall survive termination of this Agreement. 15. NO WARRANTY BY GM AND LIMITATION OF LIABILITY 15.1 GM MAKES NO REPRESENTATIONS, CONDITIONS OR WARRANTIES IN RESPECT OF THE GM SOFTWARE, THE DOCUMENTATION, END USER DATA, VEHICLE DATA OR ANY OTHER INFORMATION OR MATERIAL THAT GM OR ANY GM REPRESENTATIVES MAKES AVAILABLE TO YOU. THE GM SOFTWARE, DOCUMENTATION, END USER DATA, VEHICLE DATA AND ANY OTHER INFORMATION AND MATERIALS THAT GM MAKES AVAILABLE TO YOU IS PROVIDED “AS IS” AND “AS AVAILABLE” INCLUDING WITH ALL FAULTS AND ERRORS AS MAY OCCUR THEREIN. GM, ON BEHALF OF ITSELF AND ALL GM REPRESENTATIVES, EXPLICITLY DISCLAIMS ALL WARRANTIES AND CONDITIONS, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, SATISFACTORY QUALITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE IN RESPECT OF THE SERVICES, THE SOFTWARE OR THE HARDWARE, NON-INFRINGEMENT AND ACCURACY. 15.2 GM DOES NOT PROVIDE ANY WARRANTIES REGARDING THE AVAILABILITY, PERFORMANCE OR OPERATION OF THE GM SOFTWARE, THE APPSHOP OR ANY OF GM’S PERFORMANCE OR PROCEDURES IN CONNECTION WITH THE APPSHOP OR THIS AGREEMENT. GM DOES NOT PROVIDE ANY WARRANTY AS TO THE AVAILABILITY OF THE APPSHOP OR THAT THE APPSHOP WILL OPERATE WITHOUT INTERRUPTION OR ERROR FREE. GM DOS NOT WARRANT THAT THE APPSHOP WILL CONTINUE IN EXISTENCE FOR ANY PERIOD OF TIME AND DOES NOT WARRANT THAT FUTURE OPERATION OF THE APPSHOP WILL BE COMPATIBLE WITH CURRENT OPERATION OR APPLICATIONS. 15.3 GM DOES NOT WARRANT THAT THE GM SOFTWARE WILL OPERATE PROPERLY ON YOUR EQUIPMENT AND YOU AND ONLY YOU WILL BE RESPONSIBLE FOR ALL REPAIRS TO YOUR EQUIPMENT AND ANY OTHER LOSSES ACTUALLY OR ALLEGEDLY CAUSED BY THE GM SOFTWARE. 15.4 GM DOES NOT PROVIDE ANY GUARANTEE, CONDITION OR WARRANTY OF THE ACCURACY OF ANY DATA MADE AVAILABLE TO ANY APPLICATION THAT YOU PROVIDE, WHETHER THE DATA IS LOCATION DATA OR ANY OTHER DATA AVAILABLE TO YOUR APPLICATION. 15.5 SOME JURISDICTIONS LIMIT OR DO NOT ALLOW THE DISCLAIMER OF IMPLIED OR OTHER WARRANTIES, SO SOME OF THE ABOVE DISCLAIMERS MAY NOT APPLY TO THE EXTENT SUCH JURISDICTION’S LAW IS APPLICABLE TO THIS AGREEMENT, IN WHICH CASE GM’S WARRANTIES SHALL BE LIMITED TO THE EXTENT PERMITTED BY LAW. 15.6 TO THE EXTENT ALLOWED BY LAW, GM WILL NOT BE LIABLE IN ANY WAY IN CONNECTION WITH THIS AGREEMENT, YOUR APPLICATION OR THE APPSHOP FOR ANY INDIRECT, SPECIAL, PUNITIVE OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES OR AMOUNTS FOR LOSS OF INCOME, PROFITS OR SAVINGS ARISING OUT OF OR RELATED TO THIS AGREEMENT, YOUR APPLICATION OR THE APPSHOP. THESE LIMITS AND EXCLUSIONS APPLY EVEN IF GM KNEW OR SHOULD HAVE KNOWN ABOUT THE POSSIBILITY OF THE DAMAGES AND WHETHER ARISING BASED ON NEGLIGENCE, TORT OR BREACH OF CONTRACT. TO THE EXTENT THAT ANY COURT FINDS GM LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM IN CONNECTION WITH THIS AGREEMENT, YOUR APPLICATION OR THE APPSHOP, AND TO THE EXTENT ALLOWED BY LAW, YOU AGREE THAT GM SHALL ONLY BE LIABLE FOR DIRECT DAMAGES AND THE MAXIMUM DAMAGES FOR ALL SUCH CLAIMS IN THE AGGREGATE SHALL BE NO GREATER THAN $100.00. 16. General 16.1 Consent to Collection and Use of Data You agree that GM may collect and use information related to You and Your Application including, but not limited to, Your contact information, technical information about Your Application, including usage information and statistics and any unique identifiers associated with Your Application, and information collected from users of Your Application. The information that GM collects about You may be stored on servers in the United States, a jurisdiction that may not provide a level of protection equivalent to that in Your home jurisdiction. GM may use this information to facilitate the provision of software updates and other services to You, to verify compliance with the terms of this Agreement, and to improve GM products or to provide services or technologies. To accomplish some of these uses, GM may share this information among GM Representatives. GM is under no obligation to provide You with any data or information relating to Your Application that GM collects or processes, including any data collected from users of Your Application. Because GM provides service through wired and wireless networks, GM can’t promise that communications with end users, including downloads of Your Application, won’t be intercepted by others. You agree that GM won’t be liable for any damages for any loss, including loss of privacy or piracy, occurring in communication over such networks. 16.2 Assignment You shall not assign this Agreement (or any portion thereof) without GM’s prior written consent and any attempted assignment without GM's prior written consent shall be null and void. Upon notice to You, GM may assign this Agreement. 16.3 Relationship You agree that GM and You intend to create an independent contractor relationship and nothing contained in this Agreement shall be construed to make either You or GM partners, joint ventures, principals, agents (except as expressly set forth in this Agreement), mandatory or employees of the other. No officer, director, employee, agent, affiliate or contractor retained by You shall be deemed to be an employee, agent or contractor of GM. Neither Party shall have any right, power or authority, express or implied, to bind the other. 16.4 Audit. GM may, at any time within its sole discretion, audit, and You will cooperate with any such audit of, Your compliance with the terms of this Agreement. For sake of clarity, the right to audit includes, but is not limited to, the right to audit Your compliance, and the compliance of Your Application, with any and all of the following: (a) information security requirements. (c) Application performance security requirements, and (c) any requirements that GM provides to you in the Documentation. 16.5 Notices All notices, requests, consents, approvals and other communications required or permitted by You under this Agreement shall be in writing and shall be deemed given when delivered in hand or five (5) business days after being mailed using a reliable national or international mail service, registered or certified mail, postage prepaid, and addressed as follows: GM In-Vehicle API Website Director, 400 Renaissance Center, MC 482-D39-B24, Detroit, MI 48323. GM may change its address for notification purposes on giving notice to You. You consent to receive notices by e-mail and agree that any such notices that GM sends to You shall be legally effective. Upon notice to GM, You may change Your e-mail address for notification purposes at any time. 16.6 Severability If any term or provision of this Agreement, or of any document incorporated herein by reference is held by a court of competent jurisdiction to be contrary to law, then the remaining provisions of this Agreement or the application of such provision to persons or circumstances other than those as to which it is invalid or unenforceable shall not be affected thereby, and each such provision of this Agreement shall be valid and enforceable to the extent granted by law and such term or provision shall be deemed to be refined to comply with the applicable law while achieving its original intent as closely as possible. Notwithstanding the foregoing, if any right of GM or any of Your obligations to comply with the AppShop Requirements under this Agreement is deemed contrary to law, then this Agreement shall immediately terminate. 16.7 Waiver No term or condition of this Agreement or of any document referenced herein or incorporated herein by reference shall be deemed waived and no breach shall be deemed excused unless such waiver or consent shall be in writing and signed by the Party claimed to have waived or consented. No consent by any Party to, or waiver of, a breach by the other, whether express or implied, shall constitute a consent to, waiver of, or excuse for any different or subsequent breach. 16.8 References and Headings In this Agreement the article and section headings and the tables of contents are for convenience of reference only and shall not be considered in the interpretation of this Agreement. Any phrase introduced by the words “include,” “including” or “in particular” or any similar words or expression shall be construed as illustrative and shall not be given a restrictive meaning by reason of the fact that they are followed by particular examples intended to be embraced by the general words. The terms “herein,” “hereof” and any similar words or expression shall be construed as referring to this Agreement in its entirety and not to any particular section or subsection except to the extent expressly specified 16.9 Compliance with Laws and Regulations; Export Control You will comply with all applicable laws and regulations applicable to the GM Software, Documentation, and Your Application, including but not limited to all export control laws and regulations of the United States, and applicable to Your use of the GM Software, Documentation, and Your Application, and shall obtain all applicable permits and licenses required for the distribution of Your Application in accordance with this Agreement. You may not use, export, re-export, import, sell or transfer the GM Software, Documentation, or Your Application except as authorized by United States law and any other applicable laws and regulations. In particular, but without limitation, the GM Software, Documentation, and Your Application may not be exported or re-exported (a) into any U.S. embargoed countries or (b) to anyone on the U.S. Treasury Department’s list of Specially Designated Nationals or the U.S. Department of Commerce Denied Persons List or Entity List. By using the GM Software and Documentation, You represent and warrant that You are not located in any such country or on any such list. You also agree that You will not use the GM Software, Documentation, or Your Application for any purposes prohibited by United States law, including, without limitation, the development, design, manufacture or production of nuclear, missiles, or chemical or biological weapons. You certify that Your Application is not subject to any license requirements for distribution, export, re-export or use into any countries not subject to U.S. embargo. 16.10 Governing Law This Agreement shall be interpreted in accordance with and governed by the State of Michigan, except in relation to any conflict of law provisions which would require application of another choice of law. You and GM consent to personal jurisdiction and exclusive venue in the state and federal courts of the Eastern District of Michigan for the resolution of any disputes arising out of or related to this Agreement. If You are a public educational institution in a state that requires applicability of one or more laws of Your state, then those laws of Your state shall apply. You agree that, regardless of any statute or law to the contrary, You must file any claim or cause of action arising out of or related to use of the AppShop or this Agreement within one (1) year after such claim or cause of action arose, or You shall be forever barred from filing such claim or cause of action. To the fullest extent permitted by applicable law, You agree that any and all disputes, claims, and causes of action You may have in connection with or related to the AppShop or this Agreement will be resolved individually, without resort to any form of class action. This Agreement shall not be subject to the United Nations Convention on Contracts for the International Sale of Goods, the application of which is expressly excluded. 16.11 Language The parties hereto confirm that it is their wish that this Agreement, as well as all other documents relating hereto, including all notices, have been and shall be drawn up in the English language only. Les parties aux présentes confirment leur volonté que cette convention, de même que tous les documents, y compris tout avis, qui s’y rattachent, soient rédigés en langue anglaise. 16.12 Entire Agreement This Agreement, and further terms and policies that are expressly referenced in this Agreement, are the entire agreement between the parties with respect to its subject matter, and there are no other representations, understandings or agreements between the parties relative to such subject matter. You cannot change this agreement unless GM agrees in writing to the change. GM may modify this Agreement by providing notice to You or by asking You to view and click to accept a new version of this Agreement. Exhibit A Standard End User License (United States Version) This Standard End User License (“License”) applies to all software that you download from the AppShop and any updates, upgrades, modifications, or new versions to that software installed or used or when your computer, mobile device, or GM Connected Device synchronizes with your GM account (“Products”) or any Products pre-installed in Your GM Connected Device. A “GM Connected Device” is a device produced by General Motors Holdings LLC (“GM”), for GM, or as authorized by GM that is capable of receiving Products. “Your GM Connected Device” is a GM Connected Device that you own, lease, have access to in a vehicle that you use. If the Product being downloaded is provided by GM, then references to “Provider” in this license means GM. If the Product being downloaded is provided by a third party, then references to “Provider” in this License means the third party identified to you at the time of download. If that third party provides terms that apply to your use of its Product, then those terms will apply to your use of that Product in addition to the terms of this License, and this License will govern to the extent there are any conflicts. If you do not agree to this License, you must uninstall and not use the Products. 1. License. Provider is the owner or licensor of all right, title and interest in and to the Product, including without limitation any content, graphics, audiovisual files, processes, and code, along with all intellectual property rights in the Product. Subject to your compliance with this License, Provider grants you a limited, personal, noncommercial, non-transferable, nonsublicensable, revocable, non-exclusive license to install and use the Product in object code for its intended purpose on Your GM Connected Device, for the Term (as defined in Section 6 below) of the License. You agree and consent to install and use the Product pursuant to this License. The Product is licensed to you but not sold to you. 2. Provider Updates, Modifications and Deletions. From time to time, Provider may remotely update, upgrade, modify, or delete the Product or its services for certain reasons, including, without limitation, to increase functionality, to improve stability, to address safety or security concerns, or any other condition that would adversely affect the operation of Your GM Connected Device. You agree that Provider may at any time automatically update, upgrade, modify, or delete the Product or its services. You also agree that Provider may elect to cease support of the Product or provision of its services that the Product accesses. The Product may be removed automatically from Your GM Connected Device during synchronization with your account. If the Product is updated, upgraded or modified, whether to enhance or correct features or functionality, then this License shall apply to the updates, upgrades and modifications unless separate terms are provided with the update, upgrade or modification. You understand and agree that Provider has no obligation to provide any customer support for the Product and the use and operation thereof is your own responsibility. 3. Effect of Products on GM Connected Devices. You understand that the download, operation or use of Product(s) may: (i) have an unintended or adverse effect on the GM Connected Device, any system or software operating in or with the GM Connected Device, or one or more other Products,(ii) result in a modification or change to the GM Connected Device, any system or software operating in or with the GM Connected Device, one or more other Products, or the functionality of any one or more of the foregoing; or (iii) render all or a portion of the GM Connected Device, any system or software operating in or with the GM Connected Device, or one or more other Products inaccessible or unusable. You understand and agree that the download, operation and use of Products is at your own risk and is your own responsibility, and that Provider has no obligation to provide customer support for the Product or with regard to any effect it may have on the GM Connected Device, any system or software operating in or with the GM Connected Device, or one or more other Products. 4. No reverse engineering; re-distribution or security circumvention. You agree not to reverse engineer, disassemble, use in a compilation, decompile, repurpose, distribute, resell or modify the Product. You may only copy the Product for purposes of transferring the Product to Your GM Connected Device and operating the Product on Your GM Connected Device. You may not re-distribute the Product to other people that do not use Your GM Connected Device or vehicle. You agree to abide by and will not circumvent any security means or access control technology included in or with the Product. 5. Open Source. If the Product includes any Open Source Software, then your rights and responsibilities with respect to the Open Source Software shall be governed according to the terms of the applicable Open Source License. “Open Source Software” means software made available to others under the terms of an Open Source License; “Open Source License” means a software license that includes, but is not limited to, terms that: (a) permit distribution/redistribution of the software, including free of charge and for sale, by others without royalty or fee and allows for such distribution/redistribution to include source code and compiled code; (b) permits modifications, compilations, and derived works be created from the software and be distributed under the same terms as the original software; or (c) attach to the software and applies to all persons, entities, groups, organizations and institutions (the “Recipients”) to whom the software is distributed or who redistribute the software without the need for the Recipients to execute or otherwise acquire an additional license. 6. Term. This License shall continue until terminated by you or Provider or you cease use of the Product (the “Term”). You may terminate this License at any time by uninstalling the Product. This License shall terminate automatically at any time upon breach by you of any of the terms of this License and in such event you will cease all use of the Product. 7. Service terms and Web Site Terms apply. If you use the Product to access or use any service, then you agree to abide by the applicable terms of the service and warrant that you will do so. If you use the Product to access or use any web site, then you agree to abide by the applicable terms of the web site and warrant that you shall do so. 8. Data Collection; Use and Back-up. To the extent GM is the Provider, GM may collect and store information about you and your vehicle through your use of the GM Connected Device or GM Products. Any information collected by GM is subject to and governed by the Privacy Statement included and posted with a Product. When you use third party software, including from a Provider other than GM, third parties may collect information about you, as well. Any information collected by third parties from the Product they license to you is subject to the applicable third party’s privacy policy. We recommend that you check the third party Product's privacy policy prior to using any third party’s Product. By virtue of the third party software operating through the GM Connected Device or GM Products, the software may provide GM with information about you or your vehicle through the Software. You have sole responsibility for backing up or archiving any data you use with the Product to the extent you have the right to do so. Provider does not have any responsibility for maintaining, archiving, or providing any data you use with the Product and shall have no liability for any loss of access to or use of such data. 9. Content provided by Provider. The Product may make available to you content that is the property of Provider or of others that give Provider permission to provide it to you. This content is provided only for use through the Product on the GM Connected Device and no right is provided to you to, and you agree not to, copy, distribute, modify, perform, broadcast, display, transmit, reuse, re-post, use or claim any right in the content provided by Provider. You also agree that you will not use content provided by the Provider or through the Product to violate any law or harass any person, group or business. If the Product links you to any third party website or service, no right is provided to you to, and you agree not to, copy, distribute, modify, perform, broadcast, display, transmit, reuse, repost, use or claim any right in the content provided by the third party website or service unless you have legal permission from the third party. You also agree that you will not use content from the third party website or service to violate any law or harass any person, group or business. 10. Your Transmissions and Use. You agree not to use the Product to transmit or send any information or data that you do not have the right to transmit or send. You also agree that you will not use the Product to transmit or send any information or data for any unlawful purpose or to harass any person, group, or business. 11. DATA DISCLAIMER. The Product may use various types of data to perform functions for you. YOU ACKNOWLEDGE THAT THE DATA PROVIDED MAY NOT BE ACCURATE AND YOU USE THE DATA AT YOUR OWN SOLE RISK. DATA THAT MAY NOT BE RELIED ON INCLUDES, BUT IS NOT LIMITED TO, THE FOLLOWING: POSITION (I.E., LOCATION) DATA OBTAINED FROM THE VEHICLE OR OTHERWISE; DATA OBTAINED FROM A WEBSITE OR THIRD PARTY SERVICE PROVIDER; AND DATA OBTAINED FROM IN-VEHICLE SYSTEMS. 12. Content provided by third party sites. You understand that in using the Product, you may encounter material that you may find offensive, vulgar, or obscene. You also understand that if you use the Product to access services or websites, you may not be able to control search results that may return links or “hits” that you may find offensive, vulgar, or obscene. You use the Product at your own risk and neither Provider nor GM shall have any liability for content that you or others may find offensive or otherwise objectionable. GM is not responsible for examining or evaluating the content or accuracy, does not warrant or endorse and will have no liability for any third party materials, services, or websites. 13. Obey all laws related to operation of motor vehicle. You acknowledge that the Product (unless installed by the vehicle manufacturer) is not part of your vehicle delivered to you when you purchase or lease your vehicle. If you believe that your Product is not operating properly, you should, if applicable, use the features of your account to remove the Product from Your GM Connected Device. You agree and warrant that you will obey all laws, traffic rules and regulations governing the operation of your vehicle and you will not use the Product in any manner that violates such laws or regulations. 14. No guarantee of operation of features / networks. For services provided through networks, you are responsible for obtaining a contract with a service provider for network connectivity at your own sole cost. For services provided through networks, Provider cannot promise that your communications will not be intercepted by others and cannot promise that connections to websites and services through networks will be available to you, uninterrupted, or error free. You agree that both Provider and GM will not be liable for any damages for any loss of privacy occurring in communication over such networks or for any loss of connectivity or loss, error, or failure of other functionality provided through networks. 15. Not operational during all vehicle modes. The Product may provide features and functionality that are not available during operation of your vehicle. 16. NO WARRANTY. PROVIDER MAKES NO REPRESENTATIONS, WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS IN RESPECT OF THE PRODUCT OR ANY SERVICE OR INFORMATION THAT PROVIDER OR THE PRODUCT MAKES AVAILABLE TO YOU. THE PRODUCT, ANY SERVICE AND ANY INFORMATION THAT PROVIDER OR THE PRODUCT MAKES AVAILABLE TO YOU ARE PROVIDED “AS IS” AND “AS AVAILABLE” INCLUDING WITH ALL FAULTS AND ERRORS AS MAY OCCUR THEREIN. PROVIDER, ON BEHALF OF ITSELF AND ALL PERSONS AND PARTIES ACTING BY, THROUGH OR FOR PROVIDER, AND FOR THE BENEFIT OF GM, EXPLICITLY DISCLAIMS ALL WARRANTIES AND CONDITIONS, EXPRESS, IMPLIED, OR COLLATERAL, INCLUDING THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, SATISFACTORY QUALITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE IN RESPECT OF THE PRODUCT OR ANY SERVICES PROVIDED THROUGH THE PRODUCT, ACCURACY, AND NON-INFRINGEMENT OF THIRD PARTY RIGHTS. NO ORAL OR WRITTEN INFORMATION OR ADVICE GIVEN BY PROVIDER OR ITS AUTHORIZED REPRESENTATIVE SHALL CREATE A WARRANTY. PROVIDER DOES NOT WARRANT THAT THE PRODUCT WILL CONTINUE TO OPERATE OR REMAIN AVAILABLE FOR ANY PERIOD OF TIME AND DOES NOT WARRANT THAT FUTURE OPERATION WILL BE COMPATIBLE WITH CURRENT OPERATION OR APPLICATIONS. PROVIDER DOES NOT WARRANT THAT USE OF THE PRODUCT WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED OR ERROR-FREE OR THAT DEFECTS IN THE PRODUCT WILL BE CORRECTED. PROVIDER DOES NOT PROVIDE ANY GUARANTEE, CONDITION, OR WARRANTY THAT THE PRODUCT WILL OPERATE PROPERLY ON YOUR GM CONNECTED DEVICE, AND YOU AND ONLY YOU WILL BE RESPONSIBLE FOR ALL REPAIRS TO YOUR EQUIPMENT AND ANY OTHER LOSSES ACTUALLY OR ALLEGEDLY CAUSED BY THE PRODUCT. PROVIDER DOES NOT PROVIDE ANY GUARANTEE, CONDITION, OR WARRANTY OF THE ACCURACY OF ANY DATA MADE AVAILABLE TO THE PRODUCT OR YOU THROUGH THE PRODUCT, WHETHER THE DATA IS LOCATION DATA OR ANY OTHER DATA AVAILABLE TO OR THROUGH THE PRODUCT. IF THE PROVIDER IS A THIRD PARTY, THEN YOU UNDERSTAND THAT THE PRODUCT IS PROVIDED BY THE THIRD PARTY PROVIDER AND THAT GM DOES NOT PROVIDE ANY WARRANTY WHATSOEVER (WHETHER MENTIONED IN THIS SECTION OR OTHERWISE) RELATED TO THE PRODUCT OR ANY SERVICE OR INFORMATION PROVIDED BY OR THROUGH SUCH THIRD PARTY PROVIDER PRODUCT. SOME JURISDICTIONS LIMIT OR DO NOT ALLOW THE DISCLAIMER OF IMPLIED OR OTHER WARRANTIES, SO SOME OF THE ABOVE DISCLAIMERS MAY NOT APPLY TO THE EXTENT SUCH JURISDICTION’S LAW IS APPLICABLE, IN WHICH CASE GM’S WARRANTIES SHALL BE LIMITED TO THE EXTENT PERMITTED BY LAW. 17. EXCLUSION OF DAMAGES AND LIMITATION OF LIABILITY. TO THE EXTENT PERMITTED BY LAW AND UNLESS PROHIBITED BY LAW, PROVIDER AND GM AND THEIR RESPECTIVE AFFILIATES AND THE EMPLOYEES, OFFICERS, DIRECTORS, AND AGENTS THEREOF (“PROVIDER PARTIES”) SHALL NOT BE LIABLE IN ANY WAY IN CONNECTION WITH THIS LICENSE, THE PRODUCT, OR ANY SERVICES OR INFORMATION THE PRODUCT ACCESSES OR PROVIDES FOR ANY INDIRECT, SPECIAL, PUNITIVE, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES OR AMOUNTS FOR LOSS OF INCOME, PROFITS, OR SAVINGS ARISING OUT OF OR RELATED TO THIS AGREEMENT OR THE PRODUCT. THESE LIMITS AND EXCLUSIONS APPLY EVEN IF PROVIDER, GM OR ANY PROVIDER PARTY KNEW OR SHOULD HAVE KNOWN ABOUT THE POSSIBILITY OF THE DAMAGES AND WHETHER ARISING BASED ON NEGLIGENCE, TORT, OR BREACH OF CONTRACT. TO THE EXTENT THAT ANY COURT FINDS PROVIDER, GM, OR ANY PROVIDER PARTY LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM IN CONNECTION WITH THIS LICENSE, THE PRODUCT OR ANY SERVICES OR INFORMATION THE PRODUCT ACCESSES OR PROVIDES, AND TO THE EXTENT ALLOWED BY LAW, YOU AGREE THAT PROVIDER, GM, AND THE PROVIDER PARTIES SHALL COLLECTIVELY ONLY BE LIABLE FOR DIRECT DAMAGES AND THE MAXIMUM DAMAGES FOR ALL SUCH CLAIMS IN THE AGGREGATE SHALL BE NO GREATER THAN $100.00. FURTHER, THIRD PARTY PROVIDERS ARE INDEPENDENT CONTRACTORS AND NOT AGENTS OR EMPLOYEES OF GM. TO THE EXTENT PERMITTED BY LAW, GM DOES NOT ASSUME LIABILITY FOR ANY INJURY, DAMAGE, DEATH, LOSS, ACCIDENT, OR DELAY DUE TO AN ACT OR OMISSION OF A THIRD PARTY PROVIDER. TO THE EXTENT PERMITTED BY APPLICABLE LAW, GM SHALL NOT BE RESPONSIBLE FOR ANY THIRD PARTY PROVIDER'S BREACH OF ANY WARRANTY INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, ANY IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, MERCHANTABILITY, NON-INFRINGEMENT, OR ACCURACY, NOR SHALL GM BE RESPONSIBLE FOR ANY OTHER BREACH OR WRONGDOING OF A THIRD PARTY PROVIDER (INCLUDING ANY LIABILITY IN TORT), AS TO ANY PRODUCTS OR SERVICES OR INFORMATION AVAILABLE THROUGH THE APPSHOP. GM SHALL NOT BE RESPONSIBLE FOR ANY THIRD PARTY PROVIDER’S FAILURE TO COMPLY WITH THIS AGREEMENT NOR FOR ANY THIRD PARTY PROVIDER’S FAILURE TO COMPLY WITH APPLICABLE FEDERAL, STATE, PROVINCIAL, AND LOCAL LAW. 18. Indemnification. In consideration of Provider’s provision of the Product to you without a fee and the rights granted to you in the License, you agree that you shall indemnify and hold Provider harmless from any and all liabilities, damages, costs, and expense (including legal fees) that it incurs as a result of any third party claim to the extent arising from your breach of this License or any other negligent or intentional misconduct. 19. Disputes; Binding Individual Arbitration; Class Action and Jury Trial Waiver. (a) Our customer service department is available to address any concerns you may have regarding the AppShop or the Products. You may call us at: 1-855-440-0400, email us at infotainment@gmexpert.com or contact us by regular mail at the addresses listed at the end of this Agreement. Most matters are quickly resolved in this manner to our customer’s satisfaction. Any matter we are unable to resolve and all disputes or claims arising out of or relating to this Agreement, including its formation, enforceability, performance, or breach (each, a "License Claim"), with the exception of the matters described in Section 19(c) below, shall be finally settled by binding arbitration administered by the American Arbitration Association (the “AAA”) in accordance with the provisions of its Commercial Arbitration Rules and the supplementary procedures for customer-related disputes, excluding any rules or procedures governing or permitting class actions. The arbitrator, and not any federal, state, or local court or agency, shall have exclusive authority to resolve all License Claims. The arbitrator shall be empowered to grant whatever relief would be available in a court under law or in equity. The arbitrator’s award shall be binding on the parties and may be entered as a judgment in any court of competent jurisdiction. The parties expressly waive the right to sue in court and have a jury trial. They further understand that, in some instances, the costs of arbitration could exceed the costs of litigation and the right to discovery may be more limited in arbitration than in court. Any arbitration will be conducted by the parties in their individual capacities only and not as a class action or other representative action, and the parties waive their right to file a class action or seek relief on a class basis. If any court or arbitrator determines that the class action waiver set forth in the preceding sentence is void or unenforceable for any reason or that an arbitration can proceed on a class basis, then the arbitration provision set forth in this Section 19 shall be null and void in its entirety and the parties shall be deemed to have not agreed to arbitrate License Claims. (b) The rules governing the arbitration may be accessed at www.adr.org or by calling the AAA at +1-800-778-7879. To the extent the initial filing fee for the arbitration exceeds the initial filing fee for a lawsuit, we will pay the difference in fees. (c) Section 19(a) does not apply to any License Claim (i) in which a party is attempting to protect its intellectual property rights (such as its patent, copyright, trademark, trade secret, or moral rights, but not including its privacy or publicity rights), or (ii) that may be brought in small-claims court. 20. Applicable law and time limit for filing. To the extent permitted by law and unless prohibited by law, this Agreement shall be interpreted in accordance with and governed by the laws of the State of Michigan, except in relation to any conflict of law provisions thereof which would require application of another choice of law. If you are a public educational institution in the United States within state that requires applicability of one or more laws of your state, then those laws of your state shall apply. To the extent permitted by law and unless prohibited by law, You agree that you must file any arbitration request, claim, or cause of action arising out of or related to the Product or this License within one (1) year after the events giving rise to the arbitration request, claim, or cause of action, or you shall be forever barred from filing such request, claim, or cause of action.This Agreement shall not be subject to the United Nations Convention on Contracts for the International Sale of Goods, the application of which is expressly excluded. 21. Export compliance. You will comply worldwide with all laws and regulations applicable to the Product. You may not use, export, re-export, import, sell, or transfer the Product except as authorized by United States law and any other applicable laws and regulations. In particular, but without limitation, the Product may not be exported or re-exported (a) into any U.S. embargoed countries or (b) to anyone on the U.S. Treasury Department’s list of Specially Designated Nationals or the U.S. Department of Commerce Denied Persons List or Entity List. By using the Product, you represent and warrant that you are not located in any such country or on any such list. You also agree that you will not use the Product for any purposes prohibited by United States law, including, without limitation, the development, design, manufacture, or production of nuclear, missiles, or chemical or biological weapons. 22. Federal Acquisitions. If you are acting on behalf of the U.S. federal government or under any activity directed or controlled by the federal government, then the Product shall be considered commercial computer software under 48 C.F.R. Chapter 2. 23. Notices. Provider may provide you with notices regarding the Product, including changes to this License, by email to your mail address associated with your GM account if available, by regular mail, or by postings on the AppShop. 24. Miscellaneous. You may not assign this License without permission of Provider. You, Provider and GM are independent contracting parties. If the Product is provided to you by a third party Provider, you agree that GM and its subsidiaries are third party beneficiaries of the License and thus GM or its subsidiaries can enforce this License against you even if it is not the Provider of the Product provided that if the doctrine of third-party beneficiaries is found to not apply for any reason, the parties acknowledge and agree that while GM is not a party to this License and has no obligations under this License, the Provider is a trustee of GM for the limited purpose of holding in trust for GM the covenants in favour of GM. Accordingly, the parties agree that GM may enforce such rights and agreements in its own right (without being required to add the Provider as a party to any proceedings for such enforcement). If any term of this Agreement is invalid or unenforceable, then it shall be severed from this Agreement and the remainder of the agreement shall remain in full force and effect. If Section 19 is held to be invalid or unenforceable, then for any License Claims the parties consent to personal jurisdiction and exclusive venue in the state and federal courts of the Eastern District of Michigan. No condition of this License shall be deemed waived unless waived in writing by the party claimed to have waived. This License is the entire agreement between the parties with respect to its subject matter, and there are no other representations, understandings or agreements between the parties relative to such subject matter. You cannot change this License unless Provider agrees in writing to the change. Provider may modify this License by providing notice to you, and if you do not agree with any modification, then you must stop using the Product. Your continued use of the Product will be deemed acceptance of such modifications.</license>

	<channel id="channel-0">stable</channel>
	<channel id="channel-1">beta</channel>
	<channel id="channel-2">dev</channel>
	<channel id="channel-3">canary</channel>
	<remotePackage path="system-images;android-28;android-automotive-playstore;x86">
		<!--Generated from bid:6637954, branch:pi-car-release-playstore-x86-->
		<type-details xsi:type="sys-img:sysImgDetailsType">
			<api-level>28</api-level>
			<base-extension>true</base-extension>
			<tag>
				<id>android-automotive-playstore</id>
				<display>Automotive</display>
			</tag>
			<vendor>
				<id>google</id>
				<display>Google Inc.</display>
			</vendor>
			<abi>x86</abi>
		</type-details>
		<revision>
			<major>5</major>
		</revision>
		<display-name>Automotive Intel x86 Atom System Image</display-name>
		<uses-license ref="android-sdk-license"/>
		<dependencies>
			<dependency path="emulator">
				<min-revision>
					<major>29</major>
					<minor>0</minor>
					<micro>2</micro>
				</min-revision>
			</dependency>
		</dependencies>
		<channelRef ref="channel-0"/>
		<archives>
			<archive>
				<!--Built on: Tue Jun 30 18:10:26 2020.-->
				<complete>
					<size>859616969</size>
					<checksum type="sha1">a1f224245056ddaa89651e379efbde7357b15046</checksum>
					<url>https://dl.google.com/android/repository/sys-img/android-automotive/x86-28_r05.zip</url>
				</complete>
			</archive>
		</archives>
	</remotePackage>
	<remotePackage path="system-images;android-29;android-automotive-playstore;x86">
		<!--Generated from bid:6842591, branch:qt-car-release-playstore-x86-->
		<type-details xsi:type="sys-img:sysImgDetailsType">
			<api-level>29</api-level>
			<base-extension>true</base-extension>
			<tag>
				<id>android-automotive-playstore</id>
				<display>Automotive with Play Store</display>
			</tag>
			<vendor>
				<id>google</id>
				<display>Google Inc.</display>
			</vendor>
			<abi>x86</abi>
		</type-details>
		<revision>
			<major>1</major>
		</revision>
		<display-name>Automotive with Play Store Intel x86 Atom System Image</display-name>
		<uses-license ref="android-sdk-license"/>
		<dependencies>
			<dependency path="emulator">
				<min-revision>
					<major>29</major>
					<minor>0</minor>
					<micro>2</micro>
				</min-revision>
			</dependency>
		</dependencies>
		<channelRef ref="channel-0"/>
		<archives>
			<archive>
				<!--Built on: Fri Sep 25 15:46:32 2020.-->
				<complete>
					<size>923839106</size>
					<checksum type="sha1">8fb2624c63c34a01c27dd8085277b2a5fb8d7fbc</checksum>
					<url>https://dl.google.com/android/repository/sys-img/android-automotive/x86-29_r01.zip</url>
				</complete>
			</archive>
		</archives>
	</remotePackage>
	<remotePackage path="system-images;android-30;android-automotive-playstore;x86_64">
		<!--Generated from bid:8674405, branch:rvc-car-release-x86_64-playstore-->
		<type-details xsi:type="sys-img:sysImgDetailsType">
			<api-level>30</api-level>
			<base-extension>true</base-extension>
			<tag>
				<id>android-automotive-playstore</id>
				<display>Automotive with Play Store</display>
			</tag>
			<vendor>
				<id>google</id>
				<display>Google Inc.</display>
			</vendor>
			<abi>x86_64</abi>
		</type-details>
		<revision>
			<major>2</major>
		</revision>
		<display-name>Automotive with Play Store Intel x86 Atom_64 System Image</display-name>
		<uses-license ref="android-sdk-license"/>
		<dependencies>
			<dependency path="emulator">
				<min-revision>
					<major>29</major>
					<minor>0</minor>
					<micro>2</micro>
				</min-revision>
			</dependency>
		</dependencies>
		<channelRef ref="channel-0"/>
		<archives>
			<archive>
				<!--Built on: Mon Aug  8 19:37:31 2022.-->
				<complete>
					<size>1182802747</size>
					<checksum type="sha1">7aec48997addb860118a98741458922bdec606c9</checksum>
					<url>https://dl.google.com/android/repository/sys-img/android-automotive/x86_64-30_r02.zip</url>
				</complete>
			</archive>
		</archives>
	</remotePackage>
	<remotePackage path="system-images;android-32;android-automotive-playstore;x86_64">
		<!--Generated from bid:8674406, branch:sc-car-release-x86_64-playstore-->
		<type-details xsi:type="sys-img:sysImgDetailsType">
			<api-level>32</api-level>
			<base-extension>true</base-extension>
			<tag>
				<id>android-automotive-playstore</id>
				<display>Automotive with Play Store</display>
			</tag>
			<vendor>
				<id>google</id>
				<display>Google Inc.</display>
			</vendor>
			<abi>x86_64</abi>
		</type-details>
		<revision>
			<major>1</major>
		</revision>
		<display-name>Automotive with Play Store Intel x86 Atom_64 System Image</display-name>
		<uses-license ref="android-sdk-license"/>
		<dependencies>
			<dependency path="emulator">
				<min-revision>
					<major>30</major>
					<minor>3</minor>
					<micro>1</micro>
				</min-revision>
			</dependency>
		</dependencies>
		<channelRef ref="channel-0"/>
		<archives>
			<archive>
				<!--Built on: Mon Aug  8 16:50:11 2022.-->
				<complete>
					<size>1012590435</size>
					<checksum type="sha1">8f8309ae9e25b0c5eeb869bb0cb2515021073693</checksum>
					<url>https://dl.google.com/android/repository/sys-img/android-automotive/x86_64-32_r01.zip</url>
				</complete>
			</archive>
		</archives>
	</remotePackage>
	<remotePackage path="system-images;android-32;android-automotive-playstore;arm64-v8a">
		<!--Generated from bid:8674406, branch:sc-car-release-arm64-v8a-playstore-->
		<type-details xsi:type="sys-img:sysImgDetailsType">
			<api-level>32</api-level>
			<base-extension>true</base-extension>
			<tag>
				<id>android-automotive-playstore</id>
				<display>Automotive with Play Store</display>
			</tag>
			<vendor>
				<id>google</id>
				<display>Google Inc.</display>
			</vendor>
			<abi>arm64-v8a</abi>
		</type-details>
		<revision>
			<major>1</major>
		</revision>
		<display-name>Automotive with Play Store ARM 64 v8a System Image</display-name>
		<uses-license ref="android-sdk-license"/>
		<dependencies>
			<dependency path="emulator">
				<min-revision>
					<major>30</major>
					<minor>3</minor>
					<micro>1</micro>
				</min-revision>
			</dependency>
		</dependencies>
		<channelRef ref="channel-0"/>
		<archives>
			<archive>
				<!--Built on: Thu Aug 18 11:25:21 2022.-->
				<complete>
					<size>948247935</size>
					<checksum type="sha1">1b07fe1bc8a4f5a9b249ff12d5bf142cb43a2093</checksum>
					<url>https://dl.google.com/android/repository/sys-img/android-automotive/arm64-v8a-32_r01.zip</url>
				</complete>
			</archive>
		</archives>
	</remotePackage>

	<!-- Polestar section -->
	<remotePackage path="system-images;android-29;polestar_emulator;x86_64">
		<type-details xsi:type="sys-img:sysImgDetailsType">
			<api-level>29</api-level>
			<tag>
				<id>android-automotive-playstore</id>
				<display>Polestar 2</display>
			</tag>
			<vendor>
				<id>polestar</id>
				<display>Polestar</display>
			</vendor>
			<abi>x86_64</abi>
		</type-details>
		<revision>
			<major>1</major>
		</revision>
		<display-name>Polestar 2</display-name>
		<uses-license ref="polestar-sdk-license"/>
		<dependencies>
			<dependency path="emulator">
				<min-revision>
					<major>29</major>
					<minor>0</minor>
					<micro>0</micro>
				</min-revision>
			</dependency>
		</dependencies>
		<channelRef ref="channel-0"/>
		<archives>
			<archive>
				<complete>
					<size>1602814717</size>
					<checksum>07d5afc3a61d8d6a56c014ff70c94bf8b5a5662d</checksum>
					<url>https://developer.polestar.com/sdk/polestar_emulator_v29.zip</url>
				</complete>
			</archive>
		</archives>
	</remotePackage>
	<remotePackage path="system-images;android-28;polestar_emulator;x86_64">
		<type-details xsi:type="sys-img:sysImgDetailsType">
			<api-level>28</api-level>
			<tag>
				<id>android-automotive-playstore</id>
				<display>Polestar 2</display>
			</tag>
			<vendor>
				<id>polestar</id>
				<display>Polestar</display>
			</vendor>
			<abi>x86_64</abi>
		</type-details>
		<revision>
			<major>2</major>
		</revision>
		<display-name>Polestar 2</display-name>
		<uses-license ref="polestar-sdk-license"/>
		<dependencies>
			<dependency path="emulator">
				<min-revision>
					<major>29</major>
					<minor>0</minor>
					<micro>0</micro>
				</min-revision>
			</dependency>
		</dependencies>
		<channelRef ref="channel-0"/>
		<archives>
			<archive>
				<complete>
					<size>1279121006</size>
					<checksum>bbd8868c2616fa1ac4b95b0a1bf35d74139b4697</checksum>
					<url>https://developer.polestar.com/sdk/polestar_emulator_v28.zip</url>
				</complete>
			</archive>
		</archives>
	</remotePackage>

	<!-- Volvo section -->
	<remotePackage path="system-images;android-29;ihu_emulator_volvo_car;x86_64">
		<type-details xsi:type="sys-img:sysImgDetailsType">
			<api-level>29</api-level>
			<tag>
				<id>android-automotive-playstore</id>
				<display>Volvo XC40</display>
			</tag>
			<vendor>
				<id>volvocars</id>
				<display>VolvoCars</display>
			</vendor>
			<abi>x86_64</abi>
		</type-details>
		<revision>
			<major>1</major>
		</revision>
		<display-name>Volvo XC40</display-name>
		<uses-license ref="volvo-sdk-license"/>
		<dependencies>
			<dependency path="emulator">
				<min-revision>
					<major>29</major>
					<minor>0</minor>
					<micro>0</micro>
				</min-revision>
			</dependency>
		</dependencies>
		<channelRef ref="channel-0"/>
		<archives>
			<archive>
				<complete>
					<size>1472000920</size>
					<checksum>ccfc7782bf2f8ee3d9b3878075ae303e14f42c9e</checksum>
					<url>https://www.volvocars.com/static/shared/android/ihu_emulator_volvo_car_signed.zip</url>
				</complete>
			</archive>
		</archives>
	</remotePackage>

	<!-- GM section -->
	<remotePackage path="system-images;android-29;final-automotive;x86_64">
		<type-details xsi:type="sys-img:sysImgDetailsType">
			<api-level>29</api-level>
			<tag>
				<id>android-automotive</id>
				<display>GM SUV MY22</display>
			</tag>
			<vendor>
				<id>gm</id>
				<display>GM</display>
			</vendor>
			<abi>x86_64</abi>
		</type-details>
		<revision>
			<major>1</major>
		</revision>
		<display-name>GM SUV MY22</display-name>
		<uses-license ref="final-sdk-license"/>
		<dependencies>
			<dependency path="emulator">
				<min-revision>
					<major>29</major>
					<minor>0</minor>
					<micro>0</micro>
				</min-revision>
			</dependency>
		</dependencies>
		<channelRef ref="channel-0"/>
		<archives>
			<archive>
				<complete>
					<size>1812838623</size>
					<checksum>e1a178b45d7dbb4e9087c385ea7371c1d787c14b</checksum>
					<url>https://developer.gm.com/downloads/full_gminfo37_car_emu_user_03-04-2022_W152I-Y164.2.2-QIHM22BP-543_weekly.zip</url>
				</complete>
			</archive>
		</archives>
	</remotePackage>
	<remotePackage path="system-images;android-29;final-automotive;x86_64">
		<type-details xsi:type="sys-img:sysImgDetailsType">
			<api-level>29</api-level>
			<tag>
				<id>android-automotive</id>
				<display>GM SUV MY22</display>
			</tag>
			<vendor>
				<id>gm</id>
				<display>GM</display>
			</vendor>
			<abi>x86_64</abi>
		</type-details>
		<revision>
			<major>1</major>
		</revision>
		<display-name>GM SUV MY22</display-name>
		<uses-license ref="final-sdk-license"/>
		<dependencies>
			<dependency path="emulator">
				<min-revision>
					<major>29</major>
					<minor>0</minor>
					<micro>0</micro>
				</min-revision>
			</dependency>
		</dependencies>
		<channelRef ref="channel-0"/>
		<archives>
			<archive>
				<complete>
					<size>1853432059</size>
					<checksum>35abec09e29ebd4f7ca4742edff633174c7b4b06</checksum>
					<url>https://developer.gm.com/downloads/full_gminfo38_car_emu_user_03-04-2022_W152I-Y164.2.2-QIHM22BP-543_weekly.zip</url>
				</complete>
			</archive>
		</archives>
	</remotePackage>
	<remotePackage path="system-images;android-30;GM_Lyriq;x86_64">
		<type-details xsi:type="sys-img:sysImgDetailsType">
			<api-level>30</api-level>
			<tag>
				<id>android-automotive</id>
				<display>GM Cad Lyriq SUV MY23</display>
			</tag>
			<vendor>
				<id>gm</id>
				<display>GM</display>
			</vendor>
			<abi>x86_64</abi>
		</type-details>
		<revision>
			<major>1</major>
		</revision>
		<display-name>GM Cad Lyriq SUV MY23</display-name>
		<uses-license ref="final-sdk-license"/>
		<dependencies>
			<dependency path="emulator">
				<min-revision>
					<major>30</major>
					<minor>0</minor>
					<micro>0</micro>
				</min-revision>
			</dependency>
		</dependencies>
		<channelRef ref="channel-0"/>
		<archives>
			<archive>
				<complete>
					<size>1939154495</size>
					<checksum>0d06d2dedd8c9f7de401d6ad3f4001699936c099</checksum>
					<url>https://developer.gm.com/downloads/L233_R_Cad_05-31-2022_1654055003.zip</url>
				</complete>
			</archive>
		</archives>
	</remotePackage>
	<remotePackage path="system-images;android-30;31XX_GMC;x86_64">
		<type-details xsi:type="sys-img:sysImgDetailsType">
			<api-level>30</api-level>
			<tag>
				<id>android-automotive</id>
				<display>GM SUV MY23</display>
			</tag>
			<vendor>
				<id>gm</id>
				<display>GM</display>
			</vendor>
			<abi>x86_64</abi>
		</type-details>
		<revision>
			<major>1</major>
		</revision>
		<display-name>GM SUV MY23</display-name>
		<uses-license ref="final-sdk-license"/>
		<dependencies>
			<dependency path="emulator">
				<min-revision>
					<major>30</major>
					<minor>0</minor>
					<micro>0</micro>
				</min-revision>
			</dependency>
		</dependencies>
		<channelRef ref="channel-0"/>
		<archives>
			<archive>
				<complete>
					<size>1849444378</size>
					<checksum>0fc61675078b2e030cf68a90cfd0f24b8bd60119</checksum>
					<url>https://developer.gm.com/downloads/emulator-aegean-31xx_R_GMC_user_06-27-2022.zip</url>
				</complete>
			</archive>
		</archives>
	</remotePackage>

	<!-- Android Auto DHU -->
	<remotePackage path="extras;google;auto">
		<!--Generated from:p4 cl:438562115-->
		<type-details xsi:type="generic:genericDetailsType"/>
		<revision>
			<major>2</major>
			<minor>0</minor>
		</revision>
		<display-name>Android Auto Desktop Head Unit Emulator</display-name>
		<uses-license ref="android-sdk-license"/>
		<channelRef ref="channel-0"/>
		<archives>
			<archive>
				<!--Built on: Thu Mar 31 14:25:17 2022.-->
				<complete>
					<size>7443824</size>
					<checksum type="sha1">4e90abf932e512d6ca954b5126dd3a11e7a279e2</checksum>
					<url>https://dl.google.com/android/repository/desktop-head-unit-darwin-aarch64_r02.0.zip</url>
				</complete>
				<host-os>macosx</host-os>
				<host-arch>aarch64</host-arch>
			</archive>
			<archive>
				<!--Built on: Thu Mar 31 14:25:16 2022.-->
				<complete>
					<size>8030009</size>
					<checksum type="sha1">d4d12a2173fef608ad62b94fed3a112bfa146759</checksum>
					<url>https://dl.google.com/android/repository/desktop-head-unit-darwin-x64_r02.0.zip</url>
				</complete>
				<host-os>macosx</host-os>
				<host-arch>x64</host-arch>
			</archive>
			<archive>
				<!--Built on: Thu Mar 31 14:25:16 2022.-->
				<complete>
					<size>6895443</size>
					<checksum type="sha1">77e3f80c2834e1fad33f56539ceb0215da408fab</checksum>
					<url>https://dl.google.com/android/repository/desktop-head-unit-linux-x64_r02.0.zip</url>
				</complete>
				<host-os>linux</host-os>
				<host-arch>x64</host-arch>
			</archive>
			<archive>
				<!--Built on: Thu Mar 31 14:25:17 2022.-->
				<complete>
					<size>6801703</size>
					<checksum type="sha1">680418d5aca256cce151eb7f9527294e95b6bb8a</checksum>
					<url>https://dl.google.com/android/repository/desktop-head-unit-windows-x64_r02.0.zip</url>
				</complete>
				<host-os>windows</host-os>
				<host-arch>x64</host-arch>
			</archive>
		</archives>
	</remotePackage>
	<remotePackage path="extras;google;auto">
		<!--Generated from:p4 cl:495648905-->
		<type-details xsi:type="generic:genericDetailsType"/>
		<revision>
			<major>2</major>
			<minor>1</minor>
		</revision>
		<display-name>Android Auto Desktop Head Unit Emulator</display-name>
		<uses-license ref="android-sdk-license"/>
		<channelRef ref="channel-0"/>
		<archives>
			<archive>
				<!--Built on: Thu Dec 15 19:24:12 2022.-->
				<complete>
					<size>7572204</size>
					<checksum type="sha1">edd9d9389ac511d5f28e47cdfbf54bbcd7294d7f</checksum>
					<url>https://dl.google.com/android/repository/desktop-head-unit-darwin-aarch64_r02.1.zip</url>
				</complete>
				<host-os>macosx</host-os>
				<host-arch>aarch64</host-arch>
			</archive>
			<archive>
				<!--Built on: Thu Dec 15 19:24:12 2022.-->
				<complete>
					<size>7797329</size>
					<checksum type="sha1">4f8a3d3e32b27de1fc190d149039842e76a55bdd</checksum>
					<url>https://dl.google.com/android/repository/desktop-head-unit-darwin-x64_r02.1.zip</url>
				</complete>
				<host-os>macosx</host-os>
				<host-arch>x64</host-arch>
			</archive>
			<archive>
				<!--Built on: Thu Dec 15 19:24:11 2022.-->
				<complete>
					<size>6927985</size>
					<checksum type="sha1">5d87eb87a1421e59d528eac1f5cdd406c0b39f51</checksum>
					<url>https://dl.google.com/android/repository/desktop-head-unit-linux-x64_r02.1.zip</url>
				</complete>
				<host-os>linux</host-os>
				<host-arch>x64</host-arch>
			</archive>
			<archive>
				<!--Built on: Thu Dec 15 19:24:13 2022.-->
				<complete>
					<size>7012059</size>
					<checksum type="sha1">c27bf84e59dda7b79315b6ca2a314063feffd6ac</checksum>
					<url>https://dl.google.com/android/repository/desktop-head-unit-windows-x64_r02.1.zip</url>
				</complete>
				<host-os>windows</host-os>
				<host-arch>x64</host-arch>
			</archive>
		</archives>
	</remotePackage>
</sys-img:sdk-sys-img>
